<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!-- SPO Editorial Services                  -->
<!-- automatically-generated XML header file -->

<?xml-stylesheet href="../../../pre11-dlxsdocs.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE DLPSDOC PUBLIC "-//UM-DLPS//DTD DLPS Publications//EN" "http://docs.umdl.umich.edu/dlps/docs/dlpsdocs.dtd">
<DLPSDOC>
<TITLE>Character Sets/Representation, Bibliographic Class</TITLE>
<HEADER>
<JOURNAL>DLXS Documentation</JOURNAL>
<PUBDATE>2003-03-04 09:41:50 EST</PUBDATE>
<AUTH1>Hagedorn, Kat</AUTH1>
<EMAIL1>khage@umich.edu</EMAIL1>
<AUTH2></AUTH2>
<DOCTITLE>Character Sets/Representation, Bibliographic Class</DOCTITLE>
<VOL>class</VOL>
<ISS>bib</ISS>
<FILE>dlxsdocs-bib-character-sets</FILE>
</HEADER>
<BODY>
<BHEAD>Character Sets/Representation, Bibliographic Class</BHEAD>
<DIV1 ID="main">
<P>At the current time, XPAT (the DLXS search engine) supports both 7- and 8-bit character sets, with no specific ties to any standard or non-standard character set.  The following approaches are equally possible:</P>
<OL>
<LI>An 8-bit ISO Latin 1 approach in the data dictionary (the <TT>.dd</TT> file), mapping characters with diacritics to their unaccented form (e.g., an "a" with umlaut would be searchable as an "a").</LI>
<LI>An 8-bit ISO Latin 1 approach in the data dictionary, leaving characters with diacritics searchable in their accented form (e.g., an "a" with umlaut would be searchable only as an "a" with umlaut).</LI>
<LI>An 8-bit ISO Latin 2 approach in the data dictionary, mapping characters with diacritics to their unaccented form (e.g., an "a" with macron would be searchable as an "a").</LI>
<LI>... and so forth</LI>
</OL>
<P>The most common approach is to rely primarily on 8-bit representations of ISO Latin 1 mappings for the bulk of the characters, and character entity references for most other cases (e.g., &amp;amacr;).  A sample data dictionary using 8-bit ISO Latin 1 values is linked <A HREF="bib-sample.dd">here</A> as an example of this approach.</P>
<P>We do not yet provide filtering of these character entity set-based characters to displayable representations, but will probably use transparent GIFs as an interim strategy (as we do elsewhere in DLXS classes).</P>
<P>Currently, we offer no documentation here for converting characters to ISO Latin 1 values.  In the interim, see the <A HREF="../image/image-charconversion.xml">Image Class Character Set Conversion</A>.</P>
</DIV1>
</BODY>
</DLPSDOC>
