<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!-- SPO Editorial Services                  -->
<!-- automatically-generated XML header file -->

<?xml-stylesheet href="../../../pre11-dlxsdocs.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE DLPSDOC PUBLIC "-//UM-DLPS//DTD DLPS Publications//EN" "http://docs.umdl.umich.edu/dlps/docs/dlpsdocs.dtd">
<DLPSDOC>
<TITLE>Index Building, Bibliographic Class</TITLE>
<HEADER>
<JOURNAL>DLXS Documentation</JOURNAL>
<PUBDATE>2002-07-08 13:13:38 EDT</PUBDATE>
<AUTH1>Hagedorn, Kat</AUTH1>
<AUTH2></AUTH2>
<DOCTITLE>Index Building, Bibliographic Class</DOCTITLE>
<VOL>class</VOL>
<ISS>bib</ISS>
<FILE>dlxsdocs-bib-indexing</FILE>
</HEADER>



<BODY>
<BHEAD>Index Building, Bibliographic Class</BHEAD>
<DIV1 ID="main">
<P>You will need to identify a directory or directories where you plan to store your SGML or XML source file, your index file (approximately 75% of the size of your bibliographic information), your "region" files, and other information such as data dictionaries.  We recommend you use the following structure:</P>
<UL>
<LI>Store SGML or XML files in <TT>/{DLXSROOT}/obj/{s}/{sample}/</TT> where <TT>{DLXSROOT}</TT> is the "tree" where you install all DLXS components, <TT>{s}</TT> is the first letter of the name of the collection you are indexing, and <TT>{sample}</TT> is the collection ID of the collection you are indexing.  For example, if your collection id is "nyt" and your DLXSROOT is "/l1", you will place the <TT>nyt.xml</TT> file in <TT>/l1/obj/n/nyt/</TT>, e.g., <TT>/l1/obj/n/nyt/nyt.xml</TT>. See <A HREF="http://docs.umdl.umich.edu/arch/general/directory-conventions.xml">directory conventions</A> for more information.</LI>
<LI>Store index, region, data dictionary, and init files in <TT>/{DLXSROOT}/idx/{s}/{sample}/</TT>, e.g., <TT>/l1/idx/n/nyt/nyt.idx</TT>. See the <A HREF="../../xpat/xpat-index.xml">XPAT documentation</A> for more on these types of files.</LI>
</UL>

<P>The instructions below assume a sample collection named "nyt" and a DLXSROOT of "/l1", as in the above examples.  Please replace these sample names with your local filenames.</P>
<OL>
<LI>Ensure that your SGML is fully validated or normalized, or that your XML is fully validated.  Use a validating parser such as <a href="http://www.jclark.com/sp/nsgmls.htm">nsgmls</a> to accomplish this.  <B>NB:  Building indexes without validation can cause problems such as unreliable results; data that will not validate should not be put online.</B>  Assuming SGML, put the file <TT>nyt.sgm</TT> in <TT>/l1/obj/n/nyt/nyt.sgm</TT></LI>
<LI>Copy the sample data dictionary file <A HREF="bib-sample.dd"><TT>bib-sample.dd</TT></A> to <TT>/l1/idx/n/nyt/</TT> and rename as <TT>nyt.dd</TT></LI>
<LI>Edit the <TT>nyt.dd</TT> file to replace<OL>
<LI><TT>b/bib-sample/bib-sample.sgm</TT> with <TT>n/nyt/nyt.sgm</TT></LI>
<LI><TT>b/bib-sample/bib-sample.idx</TT> with <TT>n/nyt/nyt.idx</TT></LI>
<LI>and <TT>b/bib-sample/bib-sample.init</TT> with <TT>n/nyt/nyt.init</TT></LI></OL></LI>
<LI>Copy the sample init file <A HREF="bib-sample.init"><TT>bib-sample.init</TT></A> to <TT>/l1/idx/n/nyt/</TT> and rename as <TT>nyt.init</TT></LI>
<LI>Index your collection using the following command, replacing the value <TT>10m</TT> with an appropriate amount of memory.  Please see <A HREF="../../xpat/xpat-index.xml">XPAT documentation</A> to determine how much memory to allocate.<BR/>
&#0160;&#0160;&#0160;&#0160;<TT>xpatbld -m 10m -D /l1/idx/n/nyt/nyt.dd</TT>
</LI>
<LI>Create your region files by issuing the following command.<BR/>
&#0160;&#0160;&#0160;&#0160;<TT>multirgn -f -D /l1/idx/n/nyt.dd -t bib-regions.tags</TT><BR/>
The file <A HREF="bib-regions.tags">bib-regions.tags</A> can be located in any directory and can be deleted after the regions have been indexed.  DLPS keeps a copy of this file in <TT>/l1/obj/lib/sgml/bib-regions.tags</TT></LI> 
</OL>

<P>You have now built indexes and region files for your collection.  You can test that things are properly indexed by issuing the command<BR/>
&#0160;&#0160;&#0160;&#0160;<TT>xpat /l1/idx/n/nyt/nyt.dd</TT><BR/>
and then searching a common word (e.g., "<TT>the</TT>") and<BR/>
&#0160;&#0160;&#0160;&#0160;<TT>region A</TT><BR/>Strategically, it is good to test this from a directory other than the one you indexed in, to ensure that relative or absolute paths are resolving appropriately.</P>
</DIV1>
</BODY>
</DLPSDOC>
