<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!-- SPO Editorial Services                  -->
<!-- automatically-generated XML header file -->

<?xml-stylesheet href="../../../pre11-dlxsdocs.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE DLPSDOC PUBLIC "-//UM-DLPS//DTD DLPS Publications//EN" "http://docs.umdl.umich.edu/dlps/docs/dlpsdocs.dtd">
<DLPSDOC>
<TITLE>Converting Collections to  Text Class</TITLE>
<HEADER>
<JOURNAL>DLXS Documentation</JOURNAL>
<PUBDATE>2002-05-23 16:04:39 EDT</PUBDATE>
<AUTH1>Libner, Kelsey</AUTH1>
<AUTH2></AUTH2>
<DOCTITLE>Converting Collections to  Text Class</DOCTITLE>
<VOL>class</VOL>
<ISS>text</ISS>
<FILE>dlxsdocs-tc-convert</FILE>
</HEADER>
<BODY>
    <BHEAD>
    Converting collections to Text Class
  </BHEAD>
    <DIV1>
      <H1><A NAME="TOP">Overview:</A></H1>
      <P>The task is to conform an SGML-encoded collection to the Text Class DTD while preserving and enhancing the structure of the source files as much as possible.</P>
      <TABLE BORDER="1" CELLPADDING="6" WIDTH="90%">
        <TBODY>
          <TR>
            <TD>
          <TABLE WIDTH="100%"><TBODY>
                  <TR>
                    <TD><B><A HREF="#STEP1">Step 1</A></B></TD>
                    <TD><B>Convert non-XML-compliant character entities using <TT>sgml2xml.pl</TT></B></TD>
                  </TR>
                  <TR>
                    <TD><B><A HREF="#STEP2">Step 2</A></B></TD>
                    <TD>
                  <B>Convert source files to XML using <TT>sx</TT>
                  </B>
                </TD>
                  </TR>
                  <TR>
                    <TD>
                  <B>
                    <A HREF="#STEP3A">Step 3a</A>
                  </B>
                </TD>
                    <TD>
                  <B>Generate a quick-and-dirty overview of element use in source files
using <TT>xpatgen.pl</TT>
                  </B>
                </TD>
                  </TR>
                  <TR>
                    <TD>
                  <B>
                    <A HREF="#STEP3B">Step 3b</A>
                  </B>
                </TD>
                    <TD>
                  <B>Get a summary of elements and corresponding attributes in vendor DTD using <TT>dtdparse.pl</TT>
                  </B>
                </TD>
                  </TR>
                  <TR>
                    <TD>
                  <B>
                    <A HREF="#STEP4">Step 4</A>
                  </B>
                </TD>
                    <TD>
                  <B>Develop XSLT script for conforming source files to Text Class DTD</B>
                </TD>
                  </TR>
                  <TR>
                    <TD>
                  <B>
                    <A HREF="#STEP5">Step 5</A>
                  </B>
                </TD>
                    <TD>
                  <B>Transform source files</B>
                </TD>
                  </TR>
                  <TR>
                    <TD>
                  <B>
                    <A HREF="#STEP6A">Step 6a</A>
                  </B>
                </TD>
                    <TD>
                  <B>Convert transformed files back to SGML using <TT>xml2sgml.pl</TT>
                  </B>
                </TD>
                  </TR>
                  <TR>
                    <TD>
                  <B>
                    <A HREF="#STEP6B">Step 6b</A>
                  </B>
                </TD>
                    <TD>
                  <B>Validate transformed files against Text Class DTD using <TT>nsgmls</TT>
                  </B>
                </TD>
                  </TR>
                  <TR>
                    <TD><B><A HREF="tc-indexing.xml">External link</A></B></TD>
                    <TD>Index collection</TD>
                  </TR>
                  <TR>
                    <TD>
                  <B>
                    <A HREF="#STEP6C">Step 6c</A>
                  </B>
                </TD>
                    <TD>
                  <B>Check integrity of transformed files: examine element counts using
<TT>xpatgen.pl</TT>
                  </B>
                </TD>
                  </TR>
                </TBODY></TABLE>
          </TD>
          </TR>
        </TBODY></TABLE>
      <BR/>
      <TABLE BORDER="1" CELLPADDING="6" WIDTH="90%"><TBODY>
          <TR>
            <TD>
            <H1>Typographic conventions:</H1>
            <UL>
                <LI>
Files, commands, and URLs appear in this <B>
                  <TT>bold fixed width font</TT>
                </B>.</LI>
                <LI>
Generic arguments and variables are in
<I>
                  <B>
                    <TT>BOLD FIXED WIDTH ALL CAPS ITALICS</TT>
                  </B>.</I>
              </LI>
              </UL>
          </TD>
          </TR>
        </TBODY></TABLE>
      <P>When batch-processing source files, copy them after each step (placing them in a well-named directory) so that expensive steps don't have to be
re-executed to recover an earlier state. Example directory names: 0raw, 1sgml2xml, 2sx, 3xslt, 4xml2sgml.  An overview of helpful tools for this conversion is available <A HREF="examples/tools.html">here</A>.</P>
      <H1><A NAME="STEP1"/>1. Convert non-XML-compliant character entities using <A HREF="examples/sgml2xml.pl.txt">sgml2xml.pl</A></H1>
      <BLOCKQUOTE>
        <P>Usage:</P>
        <BLOCKQUOTE><P><B>
            <TT>perl sgml2xml.pl <I>SOURCEFILE</I>
            </TT>
          </B></P>
        </BLOCKQUOTE>
        <P>E.g., for the first source file in the collection Early English Prose Fiction (EEPF)</P>
        <BLOCKQUOTE><P><B>
            <TT>perl sgml2xml.pl eepf01.pgp</TT>
          </B>
        </P></BLOCKQUOTE>
        <P>The script does an in-place modification of the sourcefile, so that the output file is the same as the input file. Thus it's advisable to
save the original source files, copy them into a directory for processing (e.g., one called sgml2xml) and run the script on the copied files.
This way, you still have a copy of the source files in their original state.</P>
        <TABLE BORDER="1" CELLPADDING="6" WIDTH="90%"><TBODY>
            <TR>
              <TD><P>What's going on here?</P>
XML only allows limited use of character entities in the form <B>
              <TT>&amp;entityname;</TT>
            </B>
. An example of a non-compliant entity is <B>
              <TT>&amp;hyphen;</TT>
            </B>
. The script <B>
              <TT>sgml2xml.pl</TT>
            </B> handles such entities by converting
the initial ampersand to <B>
              <TT>&amp;amp;</TT>
            </B>. For example:
<BLOCKQUOTE>
                  <P><B>
                <TT>&amp;mdash;</TT>
              </B> becomes <B>
                <TT>&amp;amp;mdash;</TT>
              </B>
              <BR/>
              <B>
                <TT>&amp;amp;</TT>
              </B> becomes <B>
                <TT>&amp;amp;amp;</TT>
              </B>
            </P></BLOCKQUOTE>
This preserves character entity information without using non-XML-compliant entities. Later in this conversion process, character entities will
be recovered by globally converting <B>
              <TT>&amp;amp;</TT>
            </B> back to the
<B>
              <TT>&amp;</TT>
            </B>
character.
<P>See <A HREF="http://www.w3.org/TR/2000/REC-xml-20001006.html#syntax">section
2.4 of the XML specification</A> for more information on the use of character
entities in XML.</P>
          </TD>
            </TR>
          </TBODY></TABLE></BLOCKQUOTE>
      <H1>
        <A NAME="STEP2"/>2. <B>Convert source files to XML using <A HREF="http://www.jclark.com/sp/sx.htm">sx</A>
        </B>
      </H1>
      <BLOCKQUOTE><P>Usage:</P>
        <BLOCKQUOTE><P>
          <B>
            <TT>sx -x <I>XML_OUTPUT_OPTION</I> -b <I>ENCODING</I> -E
<I>MAXERRORS</I>
-f <I>ERROR_OUTPUTFILE</I> doctype <I>SOURCEFILE</I> &gt;
<I>OUTPUTFILE.XML</I>
            </TT>
          </B>
        </P></BLOCKQUOTE>
        <P>...where <B>
          <TT>doctype</TT>
        </B>
        is a file in the form:</P>
        <BLOCKQUOTE><P>
          <B>
            <TT>&lt;!DOCTYPE <I>TOP_LEVEL_TAGNAME</I> SYSTEM "<I>ABSOLUTE_DTD_PATH</I>"[</TT>
          </B>
          <BR/>
          <B>
            <TT>&lt;!ENTITY % entrefs SYSTEM "<I>ABSOLUTE_CHARENTS_PATH</I>"&gt;</TT>
          </B>
          <BR/>
          <B>
            <TT>%entrefs;</TT>
          </B>
          <BR/>
          <B>
            <TT>]&gt;</TT>
          </B>
        </P></BLOCKQUOTE>
        <P>The top-level tag name should be the top level tag of the source file.
<BR/>E.g.:</P>
        <BLOCKQUOTE><P>
          <B>
            <TT>sx -x no-nl-in-tag -x empty -b iso-8859-1 -E 500 -f
eepf01.errs doctype eepf01.pgp &gt; eepf01.xml</TT>
          </B>
        </P></BLOCKQUOTE>
        <P>...where the file <B>
          <TT>doctype</TT>
        </B> contains:</P>
        <BLOCKQUOTE><P>
          <B>
            <TT>&lt;!DOCTYPE EEPFGRP SYSTEM "/dlxs/prep/e/eepf/conversion/eepf.dtd"[</TT>
  </B>
    <BR/>
  <B>
            <TT>&lt;!ENTITY % entrefs SYSTEM "/dlxs/prep/e/eepf/charents.frag"&gt;</TT>
          </B>
<BR/>
          <B>
            <TT>%entrefs;</TT>
          </B>
          <BR/>
          <B>
            <TT>]&gt;</TT>
          </B>
        </P></BLOCKQUOTE>
<P>More information about sx is available <A HREF="http://www.jclark.com/sp/sx.htm">here</A>
at James Clark's site.<BR/>
More information on <B>
          <TT>charents.frag</TT>
        </B> files is <A HREF="examples/charents.html">here</A>.<BR/><BR/></P>
        <TABLE BORDER="1" CELLPADDING="6" WIDTH="90%"><TBODY>
          <TR>
            <TD>What's going on here?
<UL>
                <LI>
XML requires a declaration at the top of the document, such as <B>
                    <TT>&lt;?xml
version="1.0"?&gt;</TT>
                  </B>. Sx inserts this declaration.</LI>
                <LI>
XML does not permit SGML-style empty tags. Sx converts empty tags
such as <B>
                    <TT>&lt;BR&gt;</TT>
                  </B> to <B>
                    <TT>&lt;BR/&gt;</TT>
                  </B>.</LI>
                <LI>Sx converts lowercase tags to uppercase, eliminating any problems due
to XML's case-sensitivity.</LI>
              </UL>
            </TD>
          </TR>
        </TBODY></TABLE>
      </BLOCKQUOTE>
      <H1>
        <A NAME="STEP3A"/>3a. <B>Generate a quick-and-dirty overview of element
use in the collection using <A HREF="examples/xpatgen.pl.txt">xpatgen.pl</A>
        </B>
      </H1>
      <BLOCKQUOTE><P>This step generates a list of each element in the DTD and the
number of times it appears in the collection. This can be useful for revealing
that an element is not used at all in a collection, meaning that the XSLT
script (see step 4) does not have to handle it. This step is also
required in order to be able to compare, in step 6b, the counts of elements
in the collection before and after XSLT transformation. The collection
must be Xpat-searchable for this step.</P>
<P>
          <B>
            <TT>xpatgen.pl</TT>
          </B> requires installation of the Perl module
SGML::DTD by Earl Hood. See <A HREF="http://www.oac.uci.edu/indiv/ehood/perlSGML/doc/html/SGML..DTD.html">http://www.nacs.uci.edu/indiv/ehood/perlSGML/doc/html/SGML..DTD.html</A> for more information on the module.</P>
        <P>Create a file of queries based on the DTD by running the script <B>
            <TT>
              <A HREF="examples/xpatgen.pl.txt">xpatgen.pl</A>
            </TT>
          </B>
        </P>
        <P>Usage:</P>
        <BLOCKQUOTE><P><B>
            <TT>perl xpatgen.pl <I>FILENAME.DTD </I>&gt; <I>XPATQUERYFILENAME.XPT</I>
            </TT>
          </B></P>
        </BLOCKQUOTE>
        <P>
          <BR/>The file will contain a query for each element in the form:</P>
          <BLOCKQUOTE>
            <P><TT><B>region <I>ELEMENT1</I></B>
            </TT><BR/>
            <TT><B>region <I>ELEMENT2...</I></B>
            </TT></P>
          </BLOCKQUOTE>
        <P>For example:</P>
          <BLOCKQUOTE>
              <P><TT><B>perl xpatgen.pl eepf.dtd &gt; eepf.xpt</B></TT></P>
          </BLOCKQUOTE>
        <P>Run the Xpat queries</P>
          <BLOCKQUOTE>
            <P><TT><B>xpat <I>DATA_DICTIONARY_PATH.DD</I> &lt; <I>XPATQUERIES.XPT
&gt; RESULTS.XPT</I></B>
            </TT></P>
          </BLOCKQUOTE>
        <P>For example:</P>
          <BLOCKQUOTE>
            <P><TT><B>xpat eepf.dd &lt; /dlxs/prep/e/eepf/conversion/eepf.xpt &gt; eepf.xpt.out</B></TT></P>
          </BLOCKQUOTE>
        <P>This runs the Xpat queries in <B>
          <TT>eepf.xpt</TT>
        </B> on the data
dictionary for EEPF and saves the results of those queries in <B>
          <TT>eepf.xpt.out</TT>
        </B>.
The output will look something like this:</P>
<BLOCKQUOTE>
          <P>
            <B>
              <TT>&gt;&gt; 1: 100 matches</TT>
            </B>
          </P>
          <P>
            <B>
              <TT>&gt;&gt; 2: 3 matches</TT>
            </B>
          </P>
          <P>
            <B>
              <TT>&gt;&gt; 3: 10 matches</TT>
            </B>
          </P>
          <P>
            <B>
              <TT>...</TT>
            </B>
          </P>
        </BLOCKQUOTE>
        <P>If an element is not used in a collection, Xpat will return, for
example:</P>
        <BLOCKQUOTE>
            <P><TT><B>&gt;&gt; No information for region COPYR in the data dictionary.</B></TT></P>
        </BLOCKQUOTE>
        <P>Eliminate blank lines from the results file using Excel or Word. Then paste it into column B of an Excel spreadsheet, lined up with elements from the query file in column A. Columns A and B should have the same number of rows. <B>Save this spreadsheet for use in step 6b.</B></P></BLOCKQUOTE>
      <H1>
        <A NAME="STEP3B"/>3b. Get a summary of elements and corresponding attributes
in vendor DTD using <A HREF="examples/dtdparse.pl.txt">dtdparse.pl</A>
      </H1>
      <BLOCKQUOTE><P>This summary puts information from the source DTD into a more
human-readable form, showing the attributes that may be used for each element.
The summary is helpful in making sure all attributes are accounted for
in the XSLT script.<BR/><BR/>Requires Earl Hood's Perl module SGML::DTD. See <A HREF="http://www.oac.uci.edu/indiv/ehood/perlSGML/doc/html/SGML..DTD.html">http://www.nacs.uci.edu/indiv/ehood/perlSGML/doc/html/SGML..DTD.html</A>
for more information.</P>
        <P>Usage:</P>
        <BLOCKQUOTE><P>
          <B>
            <TT>perl dtdparse.pl <I>SOURCE.DTD</I> &gt; <I>OUTPUTFILENAME</I>
            </TT>
          </B>
        </P></BLOCKQUOTE>
<P>For example:</P>
<BLOCKQUOTE><P>
          <B>
            <TT>perl dtdparse.pl eepf.dtd &gt; eepf.dtd.summ</TT>
          </B>
        </P></BLOCKQUOTE>
      <P>Sample output:</P>
<BLOCKQUOTE>
          <PRE><B><TT>[Element]</TT></B>
<B><TT>     [Attribute]</TT></B>
<B><TT>date</TT></B>
<B><TT>     align</TT></B>
<B><TT>     lang</TT></B>
<B><TT>     pn</TT></B>
<B><TT>     quote</TT></B>
<B><TT>     r</TT></B>
<B><TT>dates</TT></B>
<B><TT>     born</TT></B>
<B><TT>     died</TT></B>
<B><TT>desc</TT></B>
<B><TT>...</TT></B></PRE>
        </BLOCKQUOTE></BLOCKQUOTE>
      <H1>
        <A NAME="STEP4"/>4. Develop XSLT script for conforming source files to Text Class DTD</H1>
      <BLOCKQUOTE>
        <P>The <A HREF="examples/textclass.dtd.txt">Text Class DTD</A> uses elements and attributes as defined in the
<A HREF="http://www.hti.umich.edu/t/tei/">TEI Guidelines</A>.</P>
        <P>All attributes in the Text Class DTD may belong to any of its elements,
with the following two exceptions:</P>
        <UL>
          <LI>
The only attributes of the element <B>
              <TT>DATES</TT>
            </B> are <B>
              <TT>BORN</TT>
            </B>,
<B>
              <TT>DIED</TT>
            </B>,
and <B>
              <TT>CERT</TT>
            </B>.</LI>
          <LI>
            <B>
              <TT>COLL</TT>
            </B>, the top-level element, has no attributes.</LI>
        </UL>
        <P>The task is now to <B>plan the transformation of vendor source files
to Text Class, preserving and enhancing the structure and semantics of
the source files as much as possible</B>. Editorial notes on selection
and encoding of the source text should be preserved. Tags and content
that exist only for the publisher's internal use may be dropped.</P>
        <P>This will be an iterative process:</P>
        <UL>
          <LI>
Refer to the vendor's printed guide to understand the meaning of tags in
the source files. Refer to the <A HREF="http://www.hti.umich.edu/t/tei/">TEI
Guidelines</A> to understand the usage of Text Class tags.</LI>
          <LI>
The grid view in XML Spy is extremely helpful for visualizing the structure
of a well-formed XML document (but it's slow for very large documents).
Using the Projects feature of XML Spy, you can make a project for the collection
you are working on and keep all your XML source files (produced in steps
1 and 2) in the appropriate folder.</LI>
          <LI>
Configure XML Spy so that it can transform individual documents.
This makes it easy to quickly check on whether XSLT is behaving the way
you want it to. But for batch processing, it's more efficient to
run the transformations either on the server or using the DOS command prompt.</LI>
          <LI>
Do directed Xpat searching to check on how elements are used in the original
collection markup. Xpat documentation is available <A HREF="http://docs.umdl.umich.edu/dlxs/xpat/xpat-index.xml">here</A>.
See also some tips on Xpat searching <A HREF="examples/tools.html">here</A>.</LI>
          <LI>
Make sure all relevant elements and attributes used in the source files
are accounted for. Take on elements in the first pass and attributes
in a second pass.</LI>
        </UL>
        <P>
          Edit XSLT scripts in XML Spy. We provide a brief XSLT
<A HREF="examples/cookbook.html">cookbook</A> showing common transformations.</P>
        <P>The distinction between <B>push</B> and <B>pull</B> approaches in XSLT
is an important one:</P>
        <UL>
          <LI>
            <B>Pulling</B> is when Xpath expressions (which refer to a node or nodes
in an XML document) selectively pull information out of the XML document.
This method, often used to restructure or reformat data, is convenient
for creating the tightly constrained header used in Text Class.</LI>
          <LI>
            <B>Pushing</B> is when certain parts of the document are pushed through
a set of templates. This approach, better suited to preserving the
structure of the source document, is usually preferred for processing the
main body of texts.</LI>
        </UL>
        <P>
          For your reference, here is the <A HREF="examples/eepf.xsl">XSLT script</A>
used to transform Early English Prose Fiction, a Chadwyck-Healey collection
of medium complexity.</P>
        <P>The <A HREF="http://www.w3.org/TR/xslt">XSLT specification</A> is available
at the W3C site.</P>
        <P>
          <I>XSLT Programmer's Reference</I> by Michael Kay (available from <A HREF="http://www.wrox.com">Wrox</A>) is a helpful reference book.</P>
      </BLOCKQUOTE>
      <H1>
        <A NAME="STEP5"/>5. Transform source files</H1>
      <BLOCKQUOTE><P>Download <A HREF="http://saxon.sourceforge.net/">Saxon by Michael Kay</A> and follow installation instructions (Saxon is in Java; Instant
Saxon can be installed and executed on a Windows box). If Instant Saxon sends an error message that it needs the Java Virtual Machine, download
and install Internet Explorer from Microsoft (even if you already have Explorer installed), making sure that the Virtual Machine is bundled with
it.</P>
<P>There are two ways to run transformations in batches. Using Instant Saxon on a Windows box is somewhat faster; however this ties up your machine.
If transformations are run on the server, other work can be done on the local machine.</P>
        <P>1) Using Saxon installed on a server:</P>
        <BLOCKQUOTE>
          <P><B>
            <TT>java com.icl.saxon.StyleSheet <I>SOURCE.XML STYLE.XSL
</I>&gt;
<I>OUTPUTFILE.XML</I>
            </TT>
          </B>
          <BR/>(For batch processing, use <B>
            <TT>foreach</TT>
          </B> command.)</P></BLOCKQUOTE>
<P>2) Using Instant Saxon from the DOS command prompt in the form:</P>
<BLOCKQUOTE><P>
          <B>
            <TT>saxon <I>SOURCE.XML STYLESHEET.XSL </I>&gt; <I>OUTPUTFILE.XML</I>
            </TT>
          </B>
          <BR/>You need to be in a directory containing the Instant Saxon <B>
            <TT>.exe</TT>
          </B>
file when running this command.
<BR/>(For batch processing, make a file with one command for each source
file, separated by newlines. Then run the command file using the
<B>
            <TT>sh</TT>
          </B>
command in Cygwin.)</P></BLOCKQUOTE>
      </BLOCKQUOTE>
      <H1>
        <A NAME="STEP6A"/>6a. <B>Convert transformed files back to SGML using
<A HREF="examples/xml2sgml.pl.txt">xml2sgml.pl</A>
        </B>
      </H1>
      <BLOCKQUOTE>
        <TABLE BORDER="1" CELLPADDING="6" WIDTH="90%"><TBODY>
          <TR>
            <TD>What's going on here?
<UL>
                <LI>
The script strips off the XML declaration at the top of the file.</LI>
                <LI>
The <B>
                    <TT>COLL</TT>
                  </B> element, if present, is removed.</LI>
                <LI>
                  <B>
                    <TT>&amp;amp;</TT>
                  </B> is converted back to <B>
                    <TT>&amp;</TT>
                  </B>, restoring
SGML character entities.</LI>
                <LI>
By definition, non-empty elements in the Text Class DTD require a closing
tag. Empty elements in XML files will be in the form <B>
                    <TT>&lt;ELEMENT/&gt;</TT>
                  </B>
(not valid in SGML). This script should be written to transform any
such elements to the form <B>
                    <TT>&lt;ELEMENT&gt;&lt;/ELEMENT&gt;</TT>
                  </B>.</LI>
              </UL>
            </TD>
          </TR>
        </TBODY></TABLE>
        <P>If in the next step <B>
            <TT>nsgmls</TT>
          </B> points to invalid empty tags,
add those tags to the <B>
            <TT>xml2sgml.pl</TT>
          </B> script. Re-run
the transformation on files as they were following step 5 (<B><TT>xml2sgml.pl</TT></B> cannot be run twice on the same file -- ampersands will be lost).</P>
      </BLOCKQUOTE>
      <H1>
        <A NAME="STEP6B"/>6b. Validate transformed files against Text Class
DTD using <A HREF="http://www.jclark.com/sp/nsgmls.htm">nsgmls</A>
      </H1>
      <BLOCKQUOTE><P>This tool by James Clark checks that the XSLT-transformed documents
conform to the Text Class DTD.</P>
<P>Usage:</P>
<BLOCKQUOTE><P>
            <B>
              <TT>nsgmls -s -f <I>FILENAME</I>.<I>ERRS</I> doctype <I>FILENAME</I>
              </TT>
            </B>
            <BR/>(Use <B>
              <TT>foreach</TT>
            </B> for batch processing.)</P></BLOCKQUOTE>
      </BLOCKQUOTE>
      <BLOCKQUOTE><P>For example:</P>
<BLOCKQUOTE><P>
          <B>
            <TT>nsgmls -s -f eepf01.xml.errs doctype eepf01.xml</TT>
          </B>
        </P></BLOCKQUOTE>
<P>Any errors will be recorded in the <B>
          <TT>.errs</TT>
        </B> files. If
a <B>
          <TT>.errs</TT>
        </B> file is zero bytes in size, the corresponding file
is valid. Once all files are validated, delete the <B>
          <TT>.errs</TT>
        </B>
files.</P>
<P>Add <B>
            <TT>&lt;COLL&gt;</TT>
          </B> to the beginning of the first file and
a <B>
            <TT>&lt;/COLL&gt;</TT>
          </B> to the end of the last file in the directory
list. If the files are too big to do this using a text editor (e.g.,
xemacs), you can do it by making files containing only "<B>
            <TT>&lt;COLL&gt;</TT>
          </B>"
and "<B>
            <TT>&lt;/COLL&gt;</TT>
          </B>" and using the <B>
            <TT>cat</TT>
          </B> command
to join them to the first and last files in the proper place.</P>
        <P>Now <B>
            <TT>cat</TT>
          </B> all files together:</P>
        <BLOCKQUOTE><P>
          <B>
            <TT>cat *.xml &gt; <I>COLL</I>.sgm</TT>
          </B>
        </P></BLOCKQUOTE>
<P>For good measure, check the well-formedness of this large file using <B>
          <TT>nsgmls</TT>
        </B>
in the form:</P>
<BLOCKQUOTE><P>
          <B>
            <TT>nsgmls -s -f <I>COLL</I>.errs doctype <I>COLL</I>.sgm</TT>
          </B>
        </P></BLOCKQUOTE>
<P>The error file should be empty. Move the <B>
          <TT>.sgm</TT>
        </B> file
to the <B>
          <TT>obj</TT>
        </B> directory, or whatever directory you are using
to store the collection object:</P>
<BLOCKQUOTE><P>
          <B>
            <TT>mv <I>COLL</I>.sgm /l1/obj/<I>C</I>/<I>COLL</I>
            </TT>
          </B>
        </P></BLOCKQUOTE>
<P>For example:</P>
<BLOCKQUOTE><P>
          <B>
            <TT>cat *.xml &gt; eepf.sgm</TT>
          </B>
          <BR/>
          <B>
            <TT>mv eepf.sgm /l1/obj/e/eepf</TT>
          </B>
        </P></BLOCKQUOTE>
<P>There is another, critical step for checking the integrity of the transformations you have run, but the collection must first be indexed. Documentation
on indexing is in the next section. Go
to that section now and index the files you have transformed. Once
that's done, continue from 6c.</P></BLOCKQUOTE>
      <H1>
        <A NAME="STEP6C"/>6c. <B>Check integrity of transformed files: examine
element counts using
<A HREF="examples/xpatgen.pl.txt">xpatgen.pl</A>
        </B>
      </H1>
      <BLOCKQUOTE><P>Open the spreadsheet created in step 3a. Label the worksheet
containing the query summary "source files". Then go to a new worksheet
within the same file. Label the worksheet "Text Class".</P>
<P>Run the script <B>
            <TT>xpatgen.pl</TT>
          </B> once again, this time on the
Text Class DTD:</P>
        <BLOCKQUOTE><P>
          <B>
            <TT>perl xpatgen.pl <I>TEXTCLASS.DTD </I>&gt; <I>XPAT_QUERY_FILENAME.XPT</I>
            </TT>
          </B>
        </P></BLOCKQUOTE>
<P>This creates a file of Xpat queries which can then be run <B>on the files
just transformed and indexed </B>using a command in the form:</P>
<BLOCKQUOTE><P>
          <B>
            <TT>xpat <I>COLL.DD</I> &lt; <I>XPAT_QUERY_FILENAME.XPT
&gt; RESULTS.XPT</I>
            </TT>
          </B>
        </P></BLOCKQUOTE>
<P>As in step 3a, copy the queries and place them in column A of the new worksheet.
Then copy the results file, eliminate blank lines, and paste them into
column B of the new worksheet. There should be the same number of
rows in columns A and B.</P>
<P>You may wish to print out the two worksheets (source files and Text
Class) for side-by-side comparison.</P>
        <UL>
          <LI>
Check that the counts of tags are the same before and after transformation
when expected. Particularly important elements to check are lines
(often L), FIGURE, and PB.</LI>
          <LI>
If you are consolidating two elements in the source collection into one
Text Class element, check that the sum of counts in the source collection
equals the count of the Text Class tag (e.g., when TRAILER and CONCLUDE
are both transformed to TRAILER)</LI>
          <LI>
Note that when an element is nested within the same element (e.g., P within
NOTE within P), the Xpat count will only be of the number of P's at the
outermost level. To get a count of P's that are nested at the first
level within outer P's, run "region P1" in Xpat. For P's within that
second level of P's, run "region P2". Note that all the P tags are
just P tags in the markup itself, but Xpat indexes them with numbers to
keep track of any nesting.</LI>
        </UL>
      </BLOCKQUOTE>
    </DIV1>
  </BODY>
</DLPSDOC>
