<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!-- SPO Editorial Services                  -->
<!-- automatically-generated XML header file -->

<?xml-stylesheet href="../..../pre11-dlxsdocs.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE DLPSDOC PUBLIC "-//UM-DLPS//DTD DLPS Publications//EN" "http://docs.umdl.umich.edu/dlps/docs/dlpsdocs.dtd">
<DLPSDOC>
<TITLE>dbconv (DB Convert) utility</TITLE>
<HEADER>
<JOURNAL>DLXS Documentation</JOURNAL>
<PUBDATE>2002-06-28 13:20:08 EDT</PUBDATE>
<AUTH1>Blanco, Jose</AUTH1>
<AUTH2></AUTH2>
<DOCTITLE>dbconv (DB Convert) utility</DOCTITLE>
<VOL>collmeta</VOL>
<ISS></ISS>
<FILE>dlxsdocs-dlxs-dbconv</FILE>
</HEADER>
<BODY>
		<BHEAD>dbconv (DB Convert) utility</BHEAD>
		<DIV1>
			<P>
				<B>dbconv</B> is a Perl script designed to merge the data in the pre-CDROM#8  groups and collection tab-delimited files into CSV tables described in the <A HREF="dlxs-collmgr.xml">collmgr documentation</A> section. These new tables are CSV tables that are then accessible by <A HREF="dlxs-collmgr.xml">
					<B>collmgr</B>
				</A> and the middleware through the Perl <A HREF="../intro/dlxs-install.xml#reqperlmodules">DBI</A>. The tables will reside in the directory <A HREF="../intro/dlxs-dirstruct.xml#dlxsrootenv">$DLXSROOT</A>/misc/db.  All institutions that have been running DLXS and using colldb and the groups file will need to run <B>dbconv</B> to get their data from the colldb and groups files into the CSV tables that <B>collmgr</B> and the middleware will use. To run it, just enter <TT>dbconv</TT> from the command line in  <A HREF="../intro/dlxs-dirstruct.xml#dlxsrootenv">$DLXSROOT/bin/db.</A>
			</P>
			<P>
				<B>Important Points</B>:</P>
			<UL>
				<LI>This program will only need to be run once, when moving to version 8 of DLXS.  This program copies the collection metadata in colldb and groupdb into a MySQL CSV database.</LI>
				<LI>There are some checks that <B>dbconv</B> performs and that you should be aware of. <UL>
						<LI>If you have collid's, or groupid's that are the same across classes you will get an error and be asked to restart the <B>dbconv</B> script.</LI>
						<LI>In Text Class <I>dd</I> is a required field, and must start with "$DLXSROOT", or the script will terminate and ask you to restart.</LI>
						<LI>In Text Class <I>objdir</I> and <I>wwdd</I> are not required fields, but if they exist, they must start with "$DLXSROOT" or the script will terminate and ask you to restart.</LI>
					</UL>
				</LI>
			</UL>
		</DIV1>
	</BODY>
</DLPSDOC>
