<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!-- SPO Editorial Services                  -->
<!-- automatically-generated XML header file -->

<?xml-stylesheet href="../../../pre11-dlxsdocs.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE DLPSDOC PUBLIC "-//UM-DLPS//DTD DLPS Publications//EN" "http://docs.umdl.umich.edu/dlps/docs/dlpsdocs.dtd">
<DLPSDOC>
<TITLE>Migration to Image Class Version 2</TITLE>
<HEADER>
<JOURNAL>DLXS Documentation</JOURNAL>
<PUBDATE>2002-07-03 17:21:57 EDT</PUBDATE>
<AUTH1>Weise, John</AUTH1>
<AUTH2></AUTH2>
<DOCTITLE>Migration to Image Class Version 2</DOCTITLE>
<VOL>class</VOL>
<ISS>image</ISS>
<FILE>dlxsdocs-image-migration</FILE>
</HEADER>




<BODY>
<BHEAD>Migration to Image Class Version 2</BHEAD>
<DIV1 ID="main">


<P><A HREF="mailto:dlxs-help@umich.edu">dlxs-help@umich.edu</A>
</P>


<P><b>General Recommendations</b></P>

<UL>
  <LI>Read the <A HREF="/intro/dlxsintro-index.xml">DLXS, Getting Started</A> documentation, and this document, completely, before proceeding.</LI>
</UL>

<P>The following is a list of the changes 
  to the system that are most likely to cause problems if you are not aware 
  of them.</P>
<P>If you are migrating from the <B>BETA</B> release version of Image Class to Image 
  Class Version 2:</P>

<UL>
  <LI><b>Pretty much every aspect of the system has changed from data to middleware. 
    You will need to run imageprep, retransform your data, and build new indexes, 
    in addition to the new steps necessary with Version 2.</b></LI>

</UL>
<P>If you are migrating from Image Class version 1.06 to version 2: 
  <UL>
    <LI>Image Class now relies on DLXS level access control. The .isaccess file is no longer used. See <A HREF="image-accesscontrol.xml">Image Class Access Control</A> for more information.</LI>
    <LI>The <B>imageprep</B> program has changed significantly and you'll need 
      to run it on all of your collections. It has a backward compatability option (see $DLXSROOT/bin/i/image/imageprep.cfg) in case you need to have your old and new versions of Image Class sharing $DLXSROOT/img during transition.</LI>
    <LI>Version 2 expects collection-specific web directory symlinks to <B>"thumb"</B> 
      to point to $DLXSROOT/img/c/coll/index, not $DLXSROOT/img/c/coll/index/thumb.</LI>
    <LI>It is necessary to use COLLMGR to add your collections to the <B>colldb and groups</B>, 
      database otherwise they will not function.</LI>
    <LI>It is necessary to run <B>makeCollectionmaps-idx</B>, which resides in 
      $DLXSROOT/cgi/i/image. Do this after the colldb and groups files have been 
      updated. In fact, every time a collection is added or the coll-config file changes, rerun makeCollectionmaps-idx.</LI>
  </UL>
  </P>
</DIV1> 
</BODY>
</DLPSDOC>
