<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!-- SPO Editorial Services                  -->
<!-- automatically-generated XML header file -->

<?xml-stylesheet href="../../../pre11-dlxsdocs.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE DLPSDOC PUBLIC "-//UM-DLPS//DTD DLPS Publications//EN" "http://docs.umdl.umich.edu/dlps/docs/dlpsdocs.dtd">
<DLPSDOC>
<TITLE>Installation and Configuration of Image Class</TITLE>
<HEADER>
<JOURNAL>DLXS Documentation</JOURNAL>
<PUBDATE>2002-03-13 11:31:54 EST</PUBDATE>
<AUTH1>Weise, John</AUTH1>
<AUTH2></AUTH2>
<DOCTITLE>Installation and Configuration of Image Class</DOCTITLE>
<VOL>class</VOL>
<ISS>image</ISS>
<FILE>dlxsdocs-image-inst</FILE>
</HEADER>


<BODY> <BHEAD>Installation and Configuration 
of the Image Class Tools and Middleware</BHEAD> <DIV1 ID="main"> 
<P><A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/">Image Services</A><BR/>
  <A HREF="http://www.umdl.umich.edu/">Digital Library Production Service</A><BR/>
  University of Michigan<BR/>
  <A HREF="http://www.umdl.umich.edu/dlxs/">Digital Library eXtension Service 
  </A><BR/>
  <A HREF="mailto:dlxs-info@umich.edu">dlxs-info@umich.edu</A> </P>
<P>Please contact dlxs-info@umich.edu if this documentation is insufficient or 
  unsatisfactory in any way. Comments on how to improve it are encouraged.</P>
<P><B>Upgrading from the Image Class Beta or Version 1???</B><BR/>
  Please go straight to <A HREF="image-migration.xml">Migration to Image Class 
  Version 2</A>.</P>
<DIV2 ID="new"> 
<H2>New in Version 2</H2>
<UL>
  <LI>XPAT is configured in the colldb (collection database).</LI>
  <LI>The convention of using image-a, image-b, and image-c for building XPAT 
    indexes has been dropped, partially because each collection should have it's 
    own XPAT index now. You could choose to use a similar method with an individual 
    collection.</LI>
  <LI>The collid for the sample collection has changed from &quot;frarch&quot; 
    to &quot;sampleic&quot;.</LI>
</UL>
</DIV2> <DIV2 ID="tarfiles"> 
<H2>Tarball Extraction</H2>
<P>Follow the <A HREF="/dlxs/tech/dlxs-install.xml">DLXS First Time Extraction</A> 
  instructions to install the middleware files.</P>
<B>Description of tarball contents.</B> 
<OL>
  <LI>ImageClass_v2-0-?.tar.gz<BR/>
    This tar file contains the tools for transformation and the middleware.</LI>
  <LI>ImageClass-docs_v2-0-?.tar.gz<BR/>
    This contains the documentation for the class in HTML, which is also on-line 
    at <A HREF="http://docs.umdl.umich.edu/class/image/">http://docs.umdl.umich.edu/class/image/</A>.</LI>
  <LI>ImageClass-data_v2-0-?.tar.gz<BR/>
    This includes the base XPAT index files which are essential to the setup of 
    Image Class. Also included is the sampleic (French Architecture) sample data 
    which is useful for getting started with the Image Class.</LI>
</OL>
</DIV2> <DIV2 ID="notincl"> 
<H2>Not Included</H2>
<OL>
  <LI>MrSID<BR/>
    <A HREF="http://www.lizardtech.com/">MrSID</A> Retrieve software is not included, 
    but is available for free from the LizardTech web site. It is necessary to 
    download the entire <B>LizardTech Image Server</B> in order to get just the 
    MrSID Retrieve software. The rest of the Content Server is not needed, and 
    should not be installed. MrSID is not required for the Image Class, but is 
    highly recommended, and necessary for zooming, panning, and multiple image 
    size functionality.</LI>
  <LI>sgmlnorm<BR/>
    <A HREF="http://www.jclark.com/">sgmlnorm</A> is required for SGML validation 
    and normalization. It is not provided, but may be downloaded for free.</LI>
</OL>
</DIV2> <DIV2 ID="docs"> 
<H2>Documentation</H2>
<P>The documentation directory was untarred in the {DLXSROOT} directory and is 
  called "imageclass". The documentation may be moved to an appropriate directory 
  based on local conventions. It is also on the web at <A HREF="http://docs.umdl.umich.edu/class/image/">http://docs.umdl.umich.edu/class/image/</A> 
  .</P>
</DIV2> <DIV2 ID="mrsid"> 
<H2>Install MrSID Retrieve</H2>
<P>Install the MrSID retrieve program in the desired location. As noted above, 
  it is not provided, and will need to be downloaded from the <A HREF="http://www.lizardtech.com/">LizardTech</A> 
  web site. MrSID Retrieve is part of the MrSID Content Server. Once you have 
  extracted MrSID Retrieve from the Content Server package, the remainder can 
  be deleted.</P>
</DIV2> <DIV2 ID="configuring"> 
<H2>Configuring Tools and Middleware</H2>
<P>Once the software is untarred, it is necessary to configure paths to match 
  the local environment. Some of the configurations may be done globally, others 
  require specific files to be edited.</P>
<UL>
  <LI>In the <B>$DLXSROOT/cgi/i/image</B> directory, the location of Perl needs 
    to be updated in all scripts. This may be done by using Perl on the command 
    line to edit the files in-place, as follows... 
    <UL>
      <LI>perl -pi -e 's,/l/local/bin/perl,yourperllocation,' *</LI>
    </UL>
  </LI>
  <LI><B>Edit</B> $DLXSROOT/cgi/i/image/imageclass.cfg, especially the following 
    variables, but perhaps others as well depending on local implementation. 
    <UL>
      <LI><B>$sidinfo</B> and <B>$mrsid</B> Set both to the location of mrsid_retrieve 
        binary (not provided). If MrSID is not being use, there is no need to 
        configure these variables.</LI>
      <LI><B>$sidcache</B> Specify the dir where the middleware temporarily stores 
        image files for delivery. Only an issue of MrSID is used.</LI>
      <LI><B>$gDefaultContactLink</B> Please change this variable so that Michigan 
        doesn't get messages from your users asking for help.</LI>
      <LI><B>$gDefaultContactText</B> This is the counterpart to $gDefaultContactLink, 
        and also must be configured for local use.</LI>
      <LI><B>$gLoginEnabled</B> Set to &quot;0&quot; if you do not have a login 
        mechanism.</LI>
      <LI><B>$gLoginUrl</B> Set the URL for your local login mechanism, if you 
        are using one.</LI>
      <LI><B>$gBookBagToggle</B> To get started, it is recommended that you set 
        this variable to &quot;0&quot; to turn off the Portfolio function. Once 
        you have Image Class up and running, revisit the configuration of Portfolios/BookBag.</LI>
      <LI><B>$gBanner</B> Set the text/graphic to display at the top of default 
        web pages.</LI>
      <LI><B>$gIdResolver</B> Set to null, i.e., $gIdResolver = '';</LI>
      <LI><B>$gImageFileHost</B> Set to "/".</LI>
    </UL>
  </LI>
  <LI>In the<B> $DLXSROOT/bin/i/image</B> directory the path to Perl in the first 
    line of each program must be modified to match local implementation. </LI>
</UL>
<P>The next step is to make sure that permissions are set properly on all directories 
  and files. Keep in mind that the web server application needs to have permission 
  to run programs, read files, and even sometimes write to a directory. Often 
  the web server runs as user nobody. The following guidelines should help to 
  set permissions properly, though local implementations may vary on requirements 
  in this area.</P>
<UL>
  <LI>directories should most likely be 775 (e.g., chmod 775 cgi)</LI>
  <LI>files should most likely be 664</LI>
  <LI>executables (programs/scripts, etc.) should most likely be 775</LI>
</UL>
<P>UNIX Shell environment paths should be added to shell configuration files for 
  the location of the XPAT search engine. This is essential for building XPAT 
  indixes and other operations. </P>
</DIV2> <DIV2 ID="augmentperl"> 
<H2>Augment Perl</H2>
<P>Please review <A HREF="/dlxs/dlxs-sysreq.xml">DLXS System Requirements</A> 
  to make sure system requirements have been met.</P>
</DIV2> <DIV2 ID="rebuild"> 
<H2>Rebuild the XPAT Index with the Sample Collection (and do some testing)</H2>
<P>A sample collection called "French Architecture" with the collid &quot;sampleic&quot; 
  has been provided for testing and experimentation. In theory it will allow the 
  tools and middleware to be tested for proper configuration. </P>
<P>It may have occurred to you that the web server has not yet been configured. 
  Before doing so, it is probably worthwhile to do some testing on the command 
  line to make sure things are in order. In order to get the frarch collection 
  working, the XPAT index needs to be rebuilt due to the fact that the $DLXSROOT 
  has most likely been configured for local implementation. Rebuilding the index 
  will be a good test of several things including XPAT. If you get errors, please 
  double check your configuration before contacting dlxs-info@umich.edu.</P>
<P>Here are the steps for rebuilding the index. You should find that the ic.sampleic.norm.sgm 
  file is already in the $DLXSROOT/obj/s/sampleic directory.</P>
<PRE>cd $DLXSROOT/idx/s/sampleic</PRE>
<P>There are several files in this directory that have paths hard-coded in them. 
  The paths need to be updated to match the local environment, and then the XPAT 
  index needs to be rebuilt. Specifically, the files below need to be edited. 
  Do not edit any others. </P>
<ul>
  <li>image.blank.dd</li>
  <li>image.inp</li>
  <li>Makefile</li>
  <li>image.cfg</li>
</ul>
<P>Most likely, it will only be necessary to change occurences of Michigan's DLXSROOT 
  (i.e., /l1) to your DLXSROOT. Here is one way to go about changing the image.blank.dd 
  file using Perl on the command line.</P>
<p></p>
<PRE>perl -pi -e 's,\/l1,YOURDLXSROOT,g' image.blank.dd</PRE>
<P>Once the above files have had paths converted, the "all" command included in 
  the Makefile can be executed to rebuild the XPAT index.</P>
<P><B>IMPORTANT</B>: if you are working under Solaris, delete all files in $DLXSROOT/idx/s/sampleic 
  <B>EXCEPT</B> for the following, which you <B>KEEP: Makefile image.blank.dd 
  image.cfg image.inp tags.txt. </B> The reason is that an index built under one 
  operating system can not be rebuilt under another without first deleting the 
  index.</P>
<PRE>make all</PRE>
<P>If it works properly, you will not have any errors, and within a minute or 
  so, it will be done.</P>
<P>The next step is to check the configuration of this collection in the colldb 
  to make sure the middleware knows where to find XPAT, the XPAT index, etc. </P>
<P>It is a <B>very, very good idea</B> to edit the colldb file with a program 
  such as Microsoft Excel since it is a tab delimited ascii file that is very, 
  very difficult to edit in a text editor. You may have to transfer the colldb 
  to a local machine, edit it with Excel, save it again as tab delimited ascii 
  text, and transfer it back to your dlxs machine. (BTW-- we're working hard on 
  a better solution.)</P>
<BLOCKQUOTE> <DIV3 id="lbtip"> 
  <H3>Tip:</H3>
  <P>If you use Excel on a Macintosh, be sure to transfer the colldb file as ASCII 
    if you use FTP. If you use SCP, you may find that the line breaks are not 
    UNIX compatible after making your edits and saving with Excel. Once you have 
    transferred the file back to UNIX, you can easily do a check with...</P>
  <PRE>wc -l colldb</PRE>
  <P>The result should equal the number of rows/collections you have in your colldb. 
    If the result is 0, there is most likely a line break problem. This can typically 
    be solved with the following perl command...</P>
  <PRE>perl -pi -e 's,\x0D,\x0A,g' colldb</PRE>
  </DIV3> </BLOCKQUOTE>
<P>The colldb file is located in...</P>
<PRE>$DLXSROOT/obj/i/image/lib/db
</PRE>
<P>The following colldb fields will probably need to be edited. At this point, 
  stick to just these until you get things up and running. The assumption is that 
  your data and middleware are all on the same machine.</P>
<P>You will find that the colldb has many rows in it. You only need to edit the 
  row for &quot;sampleic&quot;. The other rows an be deleted, but you might find 
  it useful to look at them as examples later.</P>
<TABLE BORDER="1" width="295">
  <TBODY> 
  <TR> 
    <TD width="55">host</TD>
    <TD width="217">the machine name that xpat and the data are on. the assumption 
      is that your sample data, at least is on the same machine as the middleware, 
      just so we can get things up and running.</TD>
  </TR>
  <TR> 
    <TD width="55">contactlink </TD>
    <TD width="217">change this to something other than umdl-help</TD>
  </TR>
  <TR> 
    <TD width="55">contacttext</TD>
    <TD width="217">change this to something other than umdl-help</TD>
  </TR>
  <TR> 
    <TD width="55" height="18">xpatexec</TD>
    <TD width="217" height="18">The path to XPAT on the local machine.</TD>
  </TR>
  </TBODY> 
</TABLE>
<P>If all is well, the next test can be of the middlware. The "testparams" file 
  has URL parameters in it. These can be fed to the main CGI program "image-idx". 
  If everything works, the output will be an HTML page with search results from 
  the sampleic collection on the query "paris".</P>
<P>Note that the middleware will not find any of the sampleic images at this point. 
  That comes a little further down in this documentation.</P>
<PRE>cd $DLXSROOT/cgi/i/image
./image-idx &lt; testparams</PRE>
<P>Again, if things aren't going so well, it will be necessary to review the installation 
  and configuration steps before contacting dlxs-info@umich.edu for help.</P>
<P>Next, and we're working in a somewhat odd order, you can try transforming the 
  original sampleic data to SGML (something which in real situations needs to 
  be done before building an index, otherwise there is no SGML to build an index 
  on!). The following commands will generate a new SGML file from the sampleic-data.htm 
  file. Be sure to check the date on the ic.sampleic.unnorm.sgm file. If it does 
  not update to the current date and time when the commands are executed, then 
  something is not working right. </P>
<P>But first, it is necessary to run the imageprep script, which navigates through 
  the image file directory and creates an index directory of symlinks to the actual 
  image files. If you don't do this step, the SGML won't have any image file references 
  in it.</P>
<PRE>$DLXSROOT/bin/i/image/imageprep sampleic</PRE>
<P>Next, the transformation to SGML.</P>
<PRE>cd $DLXSROOT/prep/s/sampleic
$DLXSROOT/bin/i/image/idb transform sampleic</PRE>
<P>...and if that works...</P>
<PRE>$DLXSROOT/bin/i/image/idb norm sampleic</PRE>
<P>...which generates the sampleic.norm.sgm file from the sampleic.unnorm.sgm 
  file.</P>
<P>In a real situation, you first load your images, run imageprep, load your raw 
  descriptive data, run idb transform and norm, and then build your XPAT index 
  and modify your colldb and groups (we skipped groups in this case).</P>
<P><B>Please read the other documentation to get a full understanding of the steps 
  required to put a collection online.</B></P>
</DIV2> <DIV2 ID="serverconfig"> 
<H2>Web Server Configuration</H2>
<P>Please see the document <A HREF="image-accesscontrol.xml">Image Class Access 
  Control</A> to learn how to control access (via web) to the Image Class collections.</P>
</DIV2> 
<P> jweise@umich.edu </P>
</DIV1> 
</BODY>
</DLPSDOC>
