<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!-- SPO Editorial Services                  -->
<!-- automatically-generated XML header file -->

<?xml-stylesheet href="../../../pre11-dlxsdocs.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE DLPSDOC PUBLIC "-//UM-DLPS//DTD DLPS Publications//EN" "http://docs.umdl.umich.edu/dlps/docs/dlpsdocs.dtd">
<DLPSDOC>
<TITLE>Image Class Character Set Conversion</TITLE>
<HEADER>
<JOURNAL>DLXS Documentation</JOURNAL>
<PUBDATE>2002-07-03 17:06:47 EDT</PUBDATE>
<AUTH1>Weise, John</AUTH1>
<AUTH2></AUTH2>
<DOCTITLE>Image Class Character Set Conversion</DOCTITLE>
<VOL>class</VOL>
<ISS>image</ISS>
<FILE>dlxsdocs-image-charconversion</FILE>
</HEADER>




<BODY>
<BHEAD>Image Class Character Set Conversion</BHEAD>

<DIV1 ID="main">

<P><A HREF="mailto:dlxs-help@umich.edu">dlxs-help@umich.edu</A>
</P>


<P>This document tells how to convert illegal text characters to SGML&#0160;compliant 
  characters. The process is actually closely tied to the <A HREF="image-datatransform.xml">database 
  transformation process</A>. </P>

<DIV2 ID="introduction">
<H2>Introduction</H2>

<P>The Image Class&#0160;requires that all text characters comply with
the ISO 8859
Latin-1 character set standard. Noncompliant characters may be
ignored despite the errors generated during validation/normalization
and the XPAT index will build. The problem, though, is that the
illegal characters will not be searchable in any usable way.</P>

<P>The transformation program can optionally convert any character to
any other character. This involves building a character conversion
table in the form of a Perl module. Here is an example Perl module.</P>









<PRE>
    %gCharConv = (
   
        '\x88' =&gt; '\xE0',
        '\x89' =&gt; '\xE2',
        '\x8A' =&gt; '\xE4',
        '\x87' =&gt; '\xE1',
        '\x80' =&gt; '\xC7',
        '\x9C' =&gt; 'o',
        '\xB2' =&gt; '&lt;\x3D',
        '\x10' =&gt; '',
        '\x85' =&gt; '\x2E \x2E \x2E',
        'eee'  =&gt; 'ee',
                  );
      
    1; #TRUTH
</PRE>


<P>In this example, most of the characters are represented by their
hexadecimal (base 16) numbers. This is usually the easiest way to
specify text characters that may not be displayable in the text file
that is the Perl module. In other words, you would be challenged to
type a latin small letter e with circumflex into your Perl module.</P>

<P>The character conversion Perl module is simply a text file that
must reside in the collection's prep directory. It must be named
using the following convention:&#0160;<B>collid-charconv</B></P>

<P>Our favorite example, the French Architecture collection, does not
actually have a character conversion table, but if it did, the path
and name would be this...</P>

<PRE>$DLXSROOT/prep/f/frarch/frarch-charconv</PRE>

</DIV2>
<DIV2 ID="determining">
<H2>Determining Character Mappings</H2>

<P>This section will tell you how to create the cryptic hexadecimal
character mappings that go into a charconv file. Illegal characters
most often become evident during the validation/normalization
process, that is, when the "idb norm collid" command is issued. We'll
use the "musart" collection as an example for exploration.</P>


<PRE>
    dev:musart % 78 idb norm musart
    Normalizing musart SGML.
    $DLXSROOT/bin/i/image/sgmlnorm:/l1/prep/m/musart/ic.musart.unnorm.sgm:
    <B>111</B>:<B>50</B>:E: non SGML character number <B>142</B>
</PRE>

<P>In the command line example above, the normalization process
informs us that there is an illegal character in the
ic.musart.unnorm.sgm file. It also tells us exactly where it occurs
within the ic.musart.unnorm.sgm file:&#0160;<B>line
111</B>, <B>character 50</B>. It also tells
us that the <B>decimal</B> value of the character is
<B>142</B>.</P>

<P>If you convert decimal 142 to hexadecimal, the value is 8E. So now
we know that we must convert the illegal hexadecimal character 8E to
a legal SGML&#0160;character. The question is, what should it be
converted to?&#0160;To determine this, it is necessary to look at the
context of the illegal character.</P>

<P>Continuing with this example, we would...</P>

<UL>
   <LI>Use a text editor to go to line 111, character 50 of the
   ic.musart.unnorm.sgm file.</LI>
   
   <LI>Look at the word or words the character falls within, which in
   this case is "Bartolom\216 Esteban Murillo" (Note that the EMACS
   text editor that was used in this example displays illegal
   characters not in decimal, not in hexadecimal, but octal! That is
   why it says "\216".)</LI>
   
   <LI>Determine what the appropriate character should be. In this
   case it should be a Latin small letter e with acute.</LI>
   
   <LI>Look at a table of ISO 8859 Latin 1 characters to see if
   Latin small letter e with acute exists, and since it does, we note
   the hexadecimal value of it, which is E9.</LI>
   
   <LI>Create or modify the musart-charconv file so that it will do
   the character conversion '\x8E' =&gt; '\xE9'.
   <B>Important, the charconv file must have
   executable permissions set.</B> (e.g., chmod +x
   musart-charconv)<BR/>
   

<PRE>
    %gCharConv = (
        '\x8E' =&gt; '\xE9',
                  );

      
    1; #TRUTH</PRE>
  </LI>
   
   <LI>Execute the "idb transform" and "idb norm"&#0160;programs again
   for the musart collection. All occurrences of the illegal
   character are converted to legal characters and there
   should not be any validation/normalization errors, for that
   character at least.</LI>
</UL>
</DIV2>

<DIV2 ID="whatif">
<H2>What If the Desired Character Is Not Included in the ISO
8859 Latin 1 Standard Character Set?&#0160;</H2>

<P>If the desired character is not in the <A HREF="http://www.htmlhelp.com/reference/charset/">ISO&#0160;Latin
1 character set</A>, there are a few options.</P>

<OL>
   <LI>Convert the character to a character that is similar. Perhaps
   the same character without a diacritic.</LI>
   
   <LI>Use character entities in SGML. Please contact
   dlxs-help@umich.edu for more information.</LI>
</OL>

</DIV2>
<DIV2 ID="searchform">
<H2>How should special characters be represented in the web search
form?</H2>

<P>Most of the ISO 8859 Latin 1 characters that are not readily
available on keyboards may be searched by entering a lesser
representation. That is, e with acute may be searched by entering a
plain "e". If an actual e with acute is entered, it will also work.
This mapping is handled in the XPAT index configuration, which is
beyond the scope of this document. Please contact dlxs-help@umich.edu
for more information.</P>
</DIV2>

<DIV2 ID="filemaker">
<H2>Handling of Special Characters by FileMaker Pro 5</H2>
<P>When HTML is exported from FileMaker Pro 5, FileMaker normalizes special characters to ISO 8859 Latin 1 in the form decimal character entities (e.g., &amp;#200;). The idb transformation program converts these to legal Latin 1 characters in the SGML. Although, this does not completely alleviate the need to do conversions.</P>
</DIV2>



</DIV1>
</BODY>
</DLPSDOC>
