<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!-- SPO Editorial Services                  -->
<!-- automatically-generated XML header file -->

<?xml-stylesheet href="../../../pre11-dlxsdocs.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE DLPSDOC PUBLIC "-//UM-DLPS//DTD DLPS Publications//EN" "http://docs.umdl.umich.edu/dlps/docs/dlpsdocs.dtd">
<DLPSDOC>
<TITLE>Image Class User Interface Configuration and Customization</TITLE>
<HEADER>
<JOURNAL>DLXS Documentation</JOURNAL>
<PUBDATE>2002-07-03 17:23:56 EDT</PUBDATE>
<AUTH1>Weise, John</AUTH1>
<AUTH2></AUTH2>
<DOCTITLE>Image Class User Interface Configuration and Customization</DOCTITLE>
<VOL>class</VOL>
<ISS>image</ISS>
<FILE>dlxsdocs-image-templates</FILE>
</HEADER>




<BODY>
<BHEAD>Image Class User Interface Configuration and Customization</BHEAD> 
<DIV1 ID="main"> 
<P>  <A HREF="mailto:dlxs-help@umich.edu">dlxs-help@umich.edu</A> </P>
<DIV2 ID="quicksumm"> 
<H2>Quick Summary of Changes for Version 2</H2>
<UL>
  <LI>The template scheme has changed almost completely. Image Class now uses 
    the common DLXS Processing Instruction (PI) methods. Old templates do not work 
    with version 2.</LI>
  <LI>Many aspects of interface configuration and customization are now handled 
    in the collection database and groups database.</LI>
  <LI>Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) are used.</LI>
  <LI>The interface relies heavily on JavaScript.</LI>
  <LI>There is a fallback mechanism in place for templates. If the middleware 
    does not find a collection-specific template, it uses the default cross collection 
    template. </LI>
  <LI>Each group may have a custom set of templates, though this is not a requirement.</LI>
  <LI>The filename extension for templates has changed from .html to .tpl.</LI>
  <LI>There is no longer an explicit image comparison feature. Comparisons can 
    be done in version 2 by viewing images in separate windows.</LI>
  <LI>Netscape browsers are very picky about tagging when layers are in use (and 
    Image Class uses layers quite a bit), and will <b>crash</b> if you fail to 
    do something simple like close a &lt;P&gt; or &lt;FONT&gt; tag. Validation 
    of your HTML may help resolve problems. Pay particular attention to tagging 
    structure.</LI>
  <LI>It is especially important to test in multiple browsers.</LI>
  <LI>It is generally far, far, far easier to copy and modify an existing template 
    that works than to start from scratch.</LI>
</UL>
</DIV2> <DIV2 ID="background"> 
<H2>Background</H2>
<P>The interface for image collections is highly adaptable to the particular collection. 
  The user interface translates between the end-user and the collection data. 
  Templates written in HTML and viewable on a browser interact directly with CGI 
  scripts and SGML files in order to process queries and provide search results 
  to the user. Having the templates in HTML while the actual data of the collection 
  is housed on a server in SGML allows user interfaces to differ while keeping 
  the collection information stable and secure. Basically, the SGML stores the 
  data, the CGI script retrieves the data and parses the templates for instructions 
  and then delivers the results to a browser as HTML.</P>
</DIV2> <DIV2 ID="genrules"> 
<H2>General Rules</H2>
<UL>
  <LI>The <b>default group</b> is the  &quot;all&quot; group. It is defined/configured 
    in the <b>groups db</b>.</LI>
  <LI>A collection may be included in multiple groups. In all cases, the<b> default 
    group</b> for a collection is the &quot;all&quot; group.</LI>
  <LI>Each group must have access to a full set of templates, CSS files, and a 
    JavaScript file. Groups may share interface files simply by configuring the 
    <b>groups db</b> entry for each to use the same web directory.</LI>
  <LI>Out of the box, the <b>default group</b> web directory is $DLXSROOT/web/i/image.</LI>
</UL>
</DIV2> <DIV2 ID="singrules"> 
<H2>Single Collection CGI Request Rules</H2>
<UL>
  <LI>The collection-specific template is used if available. The <b>default group</b> 
    template is used if the collection-specific template is not available.</LI>
  <LI>The<b> default group</b> CSS is loaded first and the collection-specific CSS 
    is also loaded if available. Individual styles defined in the collection-specific 
    CSS override styles of the same name in the <b>default group</b> CSS.</LI>
  <LI>The collection-specific JavaScript file is used if available. The <b>default 
    group</b> Javascript is used if collection-specific Javascript file is not available.</LI>
  <LI>The collection-specific graphics files are used if available. The <b>default 
    group</b> graphics are used otherwise.</LI>

  <LI>The web directory for each collection must be specified in the <b>colldb</b>. 
    Typically it is $DLXSROOT/web/c/collid.</LI>
</UL>
</DIV2> <DIV2 ID="multirules"> 
<H2>Multiple Collection CGI Request Rules</H2>
<UL>
  <LI>The <b>group</b> template is used.</LI>
  <LI>The <b>group</b> CSS is used.</LI>
  <LI>The <b>group</b> JavaScript is used.</LI>
  <LI>The <b>group</b> graphics files are used.</LI>
  <LI>The web directory for each <b>group</b> must be specified in the <b>groups 
    db</b>. Typically it is $DLXSROOT/web/g/group.</LI>
</UL>
</DIV2> <DIV2 ID="recommendations"> 
<H2>Recommendations</H2>
<P> It is recommended that collection-specific CSS files only include the specific 
  styles that are defined differently than in the <b>default group</b> CSS file.</P>
</DIV2> <DIV2 ID="main"> 
<H2>File Descriptions</H2>
<P> Below is a list of all Image Class interface files (graphics files were not 
  listed individually). The items with an<b> X</b> in the Collection-Specific 
  column are pertinent to building a customized collection-specific interface. 
  If building a custom collection-specific interface, it is worthwhile to try 
  to do as much as possible without creating collection-specific files in order 
  to avoid having to maintain them in the future. <b>With that in mind:</b> 
  <OL>
    <LI>Do as much as you can in the colldb.</LI>
    <LI>Next, focus on collection-specific style sheets.</LI>
    <LI>Finally, create collection-specific template files if necessary.</LI>
  </OL>
  <p><b>TIP: </b>Be sure not to create the full set of interface files for a customization 
    of a specific collection. It is best to only create the individual files that 
    you wish to modify.</p>
</P>
<table width="45%" border="1" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="1">
  <tbody> 
  <tr> 
    <th width="21%">File Name</th>
    <th width="67%">Description</th>
    <th width="12%">Collection-Specific</th>
  </tr>
  <tr> 
    <td width="21%">index.tpl</td>
    <td width="67%">collection home</td>
    <td width="12%"><b>X</b></td>
  </tr>
  <tr> 
    <td width="21%">groups.tpl</td>
    <td width="67%">group selection</td>
    <td width="12%"></td>
  </tr>
  <tr> 
    <td width="21%">search.tpl</td>
    <td width="67%">collection-specific search</td>
    <td width="12%"><b>X</b></td>
  </tr>
  <tr> 
    <td width="21%">searchgroup.tpl</td>
    <td width="67%">group search</td>
    <td width="12%"></td>
  </tr>
  <tr> 
    <td width="21%">reslist.tpl</td>
    <td width="67%">&quot;captions only&quot; results</td>
    <td width="12%"><b>X</b></td>
  </tr>
  <tr> 
    <td width="21%">thumbfull.tpl</td>
    <td width="67%">&quot;thumbnail with full record&quot; results</td>
    <td width="12%"><b>X</b></td>
  </tr>
  <tr> 
    <td width="21%">thumbnail.tpl</td>
    <td width="67%">&quot;thumbnail with caption&quot; results</td>
    <td width="12%"><b>X</b></td>
  </tr>
  <tr> 
    <td width="21%">collinfo.tpl</td>
    <td width="67%">brief collection info</td>
    <td width="12%"><b>X</b></td>
  </tr>
  <tr> 
    <td width="21%">fieldinfo.txt</td>
    <td width="67%">Description of data fields. Does not support Processing Instructions. 
      May contain HTML snippets.</td>
    <td width="12%"><b>X</b></td>
  </tr>
  <tr> 
    <td width="21%">info.txt</td>
    <td width="67%">A potentially lengthy description of the collection. Does 
      not support Processing Instructions. May contain HTML snippets.</td>
    <td width="12%"><b>X</b></td>
  </tr>
  <tr> 
    <td width="21%">noresults.tpl</td>
    <td width="67%">no results message page</td>
    <td width="12%"><b>X</b></td>
  </tr>
  <tr> 
    <td width="21%">entry.tpl</td>
    <td width="67%">full record</td>
    <td width="12%"><b>X</b></td>
  </tr>
  <tr> 
    <td width="21%"> tips.tpl </td>
    <td width="67%">search help</td>
    <td width="12%"><b>X</b></td>
  </tr>
  <tr> 
    <td width="21%">bbdel.tpl</td>
    <td width="67%">portfolio/bookbag delete message</td>
    <td width="12%"></td>
  </tr>
  <tr> 
    <td width="21%">bbentry.tpl</td>
    <td width="67%">portfolio/bookbag full record</td>
    <td width="12%"></td>
  </tr>
  <tr> 
    <td width="21%">bbname.tpl</td>
    <td width="67%">create portfolio/bookbag</td>
    <td width="12%"></td>
  </tr>
  <tr> 
    <td width="21%">bbopen.tpl</td>
    <td width="67%">open portfolio/bookbag</td>
    <td width="12%"></td>
  </tr>
  <tr> 
    <td width="21%">bbreslist.tpl</td>
    <td width="67%">portfolio/bookbag &quot;captions only&quot; results</td>
    <td width="12%"></td>
  </tr>
  <tr> 
    <td width="21%"> bbthumbfull.tpl</td>
    <td width="67%">portfolio/bookbag &quot;thumbnail with full record&quot; results</td>
    <td width="12%"></td>
  </tr>
  <tr> 
    <td width="21%">bbthumbnail.tpl</td>
    <td width="67%">portfolio/bookbag &quot;thumbnail with caption&quot; results</td>
    <td width="12%"></td>
  </tr>
  <tr> 
    <td width="21%"> bbslideentry.tpl</td>
    <td width="67%">portfolio/bookbag full record</td>
    <td width="12%"></td>
  </tr>
  <tr> 
    <td width="21%">graphics/</td>
    <td width="67%">directory of interface graphics, buttons, etc.</td>
    <td width="12%"><b>X</b></td>
  </tr>
  <tr> 
    <td width="21%">css/</td>
    <td width="67%">directory of Cascading Style Sheet files</td>
    <td width="12%"><b>X</b></td>
  </tr>
  <tr> 
    <td width="21%">js/imageclass.js</td>
    <td width="67%">JavaScript File</td>
    <td width="12%"><b>X</b></td>
  </tr>
  </tbody> 
</table>
</DIV2> 
<P></P>
<DIV2 ID="coldlb"> 
<H2>Customizing the Interface by Modifying the COLLDB (Collection Database)</H2>
<P>Please see <A HREF="image-colldb.xml">Image Class COLLDB (Collection Database)</A>.</P>
</DIV2> <DIV2 ID="procins"> 
<H2>Customizing the Interface with Processing Instructions</H2>
<P>Processing instructions are tagged elements within the interface template files 
  (.tpl) that get replaced by the cgi with interface functions and data.</P>
<P>Please see <A HREF="image-pi.xml">Image Class Processing Instructions</A>.</P>
</DIV2> 
</DIV1> 
</BODY>
</DLPSDOC>
