<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!-- SPO Editorial Services                  -->
<!-- automatically-generated XML header file -->

<?xml-stylesheet href="../../../pre11-dlxsdocs.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE DLPSDOC PUBLIC "-//UM-DLPS//DTD DLPS Publications//EN" "http://docs.umdl.umich.edu/dlps/docs/dlpsdocs.dtd">
<DLPSDOC>
<TITLE>Image Services Characterization</TITLE>
<HEADER>
<JOURNAL>DLXS Documentation</JOURNAL>
<PUBDATE>2002-07-03 17:05:32 EDT</PUBDATE>
<AUTH1>Weise, John</AUTH1>
<AUTH2></AUTH2>
<DOCTITLE>Image Services Characterization</DOCTITLE>
<VOL>class</VOL>
<ISS>image</ISS>
<FILE>dlxsdocs-image-characterization</FILE>
</HEADER>




<BODY>
<BHEAD>University of Michigan Image Services Characterization</BHEAD>
<DIV1 ID="main">

<P><A HREF="mailto:dlxs-info@umich.edu">dlxs-info@umich.edu</A></P>

<P>Image Services, part of the <A HREF="http://www.umdl.umich.edu/">Digital Library Production Service</A> at
the University of Michigan, was established to federate digital image
collections online for the purpose of campus and broader public
access. Participation in the Museum Educational Site Licensing
Project and related campus activities highlighted the existing
diversity among curatorial practices and management systems, in
museums, libraries, visual resources departments, and commercial
distributors. While there is clearly much to be gained through
standardization, we feel that the diversity exists for logical, as
well as historical, reasons (ranging from curatorial opinion to
technological infrastructure) and that it should be supported at the
same time that we encourage standardized practices.</P>

<P>Image Services has been very successful in creating a service for
the campus that enables and facilitates online access to image
collections. The term "collections" is used loosely and includes
faculty databases as well as museum, archive, library, visual
resources, and commercial databases. Organizationally within the
University Library, Image Services leverages the Library's commitment
to providing online access to image content, and absorbs the marginal
costs of providing the same services to the broader campus.
Technically, Image Services has minimized the requirements for
submitting data, and developed generalized mechanisms for processing
data that make deployment online simple. With no costs and minimal
technical requirements for the content provider, it is often just a
matter of handing data off to Image Services.</P>

<P>It is worth emphasizing that Image Services only provides online
access services for image collections. The libraries, museums, etc.
that provide content use a variety of database systems to manage
their data (e.g., FileMaker Pro, Oracle, Excel). Periodically,
content providers transfer the latest version of their entire
database to Image Services for updating online. Only entire databases
are updated, and there is no provision for the update of individual
records. This approach has pros and cons.</P>
<DIV2 ID="pros">
<H2><B>Pros </B></H2>

<P><B>Federated Content:</B> Content providers are not only on
campus, but from other institutions and commercial entities. All
content is integrated into a common system for access.</P>

<P><B>Core Categories:</B> Collection specific database fields can
easily be mapped to one or more core category sets, such as Dublin
Core and VRA Core. This increases compatibility and enhances
searchablity among similar collections. All collections are
searchable together in the <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu">Image Services access system</A>. At the same
time, the collections are searchable independently by the unique
attributes of each.</P>

<P><B>Optimized for Access:</B> The Image Services system is
optimized to provide access, without the overhead of a management
system. Relational data structures are flattened for efficiency. </P>

<P><B>Independent Management:</B> Departments can choose management
systems appropriate to needs and available resources.</P>

<P><B>Reliable Public Access:</B> The majority of the content
providers have extremely limited resources for providing reliable
public access. Image Services has robust servers, backed up,
constantly monitored, and with advanced baseline services such as
institutional login.</P>
</DIV2>
<DIV2 ID="cons">
<H2><B>Cons</B></H2>

<P><B>Currency Lag: </B>Since collections are updated periodically
and in their entirety, the version in Image Services is typically not
as current as the version for management.</P>

<P><B>No Editing: </B>Database records cannot be edited through the
Image Services system.</P>
</DIV2>




</DIV1>
</BODY>
</DLPSDOC>
