<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!-- SPO Editorial Services                  -->
<!-- automatically-generated XML header file -->

<?xml-stylesheet href="../../../pre11-dlxsdocs.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE DLPSDOC PUBLIC "-//UM-DLPS//DTD DLPS Publications//EN" "http://docs.umdl.umich.edu/dlps/docs/dlpsdocs.dtd">
<DLPSDOC>
<TITLE>The Image Class</TITLE>
<HEADER>
<JOURNAL>DLXS Documentation</JOURNAL>
<PUBDATE>2002-03-13 11:27:57 EST</PUBDATE>
<AUTH1>Weise, John</AUTH1>
<AUTH2></AUTH2>
<DOCTITLE>The Image Class</DOCTITLE>
<VOL>class</VOL>
<ISS>image</ISS>
<FILE>dlxsdocs-image-imageclass</FILE>
</HEADER>


<BODY>
<BHEAD>The Image Class</BHEAD>
<DIV1 ID="main">

<P><A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/">Image
Services</A><BR/>
<A HREF="http://www.umdl.umich.edu/">Digital
Library Production Service</A><BR/>
University of Michigan<BR/>
<A HREF="http://www.umdl.umich.edu/dlxs/">Digital
Library eXtension Service </A><BR/>
<A HREF="mailto:dlxs-info@umich.edu">dlxs-info@umich.edu</A>
</P>


<UL>
   <LI><A HREF="#Abstract">Abstract</A></LI>
   
   <LI><A HREF="#Description">Description</A>
   
   <UL>
      <LI><A HREF="#Basic Characteristics">Basic
      Characteristics</A></LI>
      
      <LI><A HREF="#General Characteristics">General
      Characteristics</A>
      
      <UL>
         <LI><A HREF="#Typical Sources of Data">Typical
         Sources of Data</A></LI>
         
         <LI><A HREF="#Typical Applications of the Cla">Typical
         Applications of the Class</A></LI>
         
         <LI><A HREF="#Behaviors of the Image Class">Behaviors
         of the Image Class</A></LI>
      </UL>
      </LI>
      
      <LI><A HREF="#General Parameters">General
      Parameters</A></LI>
      
      <LI><A HREF="#Dynamics">Dynamics</A></LI>
      
      <LI><A HREF="#Formal Data Definition">Formal
      Data Definition</A>
      
      <UL>
         <LI><A HREF="#Descriptive Metadata (text)">Descriptive
         Metadata (text)</A></LI>
         
         <LI><A HREF="#Image Data">Image
         Data</A></LI>
      </UL>
      </LI>
      
      <LI><A HREF="#Representative Resource(s)">Representative
      Resource(s)</A></LI>
   </UL>
   </LI>
</UL>

<DIV2 ID="abstract">
<H2><A NAME="Abstract"></A>Abstract</H2>

<P>The Image Class is a system of tools and methods for providing
web-based access to diverse image databases. The Image Class was
created at the University of Michigan in the Digital Library
Production Service. At the University of Michigan, the Image Class
&#91; <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/">http://images.umdl.umich.edu</A>
&#93; provides broad access to a wide range of library, museum,
archive, visual resources, and special collections. The Image Class
is specifically geared for continuous tone images. Continuous tone
images are image files commonly with a bit depth of 24 for color, and
8 for grayscale. The demands for capture of the features of the
source materials dictate the bit depth of the image. For example, the
complex features of a papyri and art images cannot be captured with
bitonal methods, and are thus captured at a high bit-depth and high
resolution. Strictly speaking, an image with a bit depth greater than
1 can be considered continous tone. Continous tone images usually
come with associated bibliographic or descriptive information, as
well as more complex administrative metadata. Currently, the
associated descriptive information is the primary means of locating
these images in the Image Class, but browsing mechanisms are also
made available to users. Descriptive metadata also varies from
minimal--e.g., only a title--to rich, with complex vocabularies for
subject and theme analysis. Of special importance in the Image Class
are methods for navigating high resolution images (e.g., pan and
zoom) and methods for using images in a variety of contexts (e.g.,
comparing images or creating small collections for study).</P>
</DIV2>
</DIV1>
<DIV1 ID="description">
<H1><A NAME="Description"></A>Description</H1>

<DIV2 ID="basic">
<H2><A NAME="Basic Characteristics"></A>Basic Characteristics</H2>

<P>The Image Class serves two main purposes.</P>

<OL>
   <LI>Online access to continuous tone images (i.e., full color and
   grayscale)</LI>
   
   <LI>Online access to image databases</LI>
</OL>

<P>The Image Class provides advanced funtionality for access to
continous tone images. Continous tone images are typically have 24
bits of color or 8 bits of gray values. Advanced functionality
includes the abilty to view the entire image at a variety of
resolutions, and panning and zooming.</P>

<P>The Image Class federates image databases at the point of access.
Access minimally includes search and retrieval of descriptive text
records and display of digital images associated with the record.
</P>
</DIV2>
<DIV2 ID="general">
<H2><A NAME="General Characteristics"></A>General
Characteristics</H2>

<UL>
   <LI>Text based search and retrieval of images</LI>
   
   <LI>Searching across multiple collections simultaneously</LI>
   
   <LI>Searching of each collection independently</LI>
   
   <LI>Useful display functions and customizable interface
   layouts</LI>
   
   <LI>Advanced image display functionality, including panning and
   zooming</LI>
   
   <LI>Bookmarkable records and images</LI>
   
   <LI>Minimal descriptive data requirements</LI>
   
   <LI>Reasonable data submission process for database managers</LI>
   
   <LI>Simple data transformation process for online deployment</LI>
   
   <LI>Uses a single data model and shared middleware for all
   databases in the system</LI>
   
   <LI>Storage of multiple image resolutions in a single file
   format</LI>
   
   <LI>Assimilates data from practically any management system</LI>
   
   <LI>Access restrictions at collection and image levels</LI>
</UL>

<P>At the University of Michigan, the Image Class access system is
administered by the Digital Library Production Service, Image
Services. Image Services receives data (descriptive metadata and
digital images) on a periodic basis from a variety of organizations
on and off campus, and fully handles the process of putting the data
online in a production level environment. Image Services has
technical expertise and resources for providing reliable online
access to image collections. This is not the only model for
implementing the Image Class, but it is one that has worked.
</P>
<P>The Image Class provides no functionality for creating and
managing image databases. Database management is handled by separate
systems under the control of the organizations that have provided
collections. For example, the University of Michigan Museum of Art
uses Embark as a database management system. The Museum provides
public access through Image Services and the Image Class.
</P>

<H2><A NAME="Typical Sources of Data"></A>Typical Sources of
Data</H2>

<P>The following sources of data have influenced the process defining
the Image Class. Other sources are possible.</P>

<UL>
   <LI>Libraries: photograph collections, manuscripts, papyrus</LI>
   
   <LI>Museums:&#0160;art, archaeological</LI>
   
   <LI>Visual Resources:&#0160;slide libraries, slide vendors</LI>
</UL>


<H2><A NAME="Typical Applications of the Cla"></A>Typical
Applications of the Class</H2>

<UL>
   <LI>Campus database access</LI>
   
   <LI>Public database access</LI>
</UL>

<H2><A NAME="Behaviors of the Image Class"></A>Behaviors of the Image
Class</H2>

<UL>
   <LI><A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/">Cross collection
   searching</A>; any combination of collections</LI>
   
   <LI><A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/m/musart/">Collection
   specific searching</A></LI>
   
   <LI><A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/m/musart/simple.html">Simple</A>
   and <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/m/musart/boolean.html">Boolean</A>
   searching</LI>
   
   <LI>Results viewing as <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?c=bhl;type=simple;xc=1;q1=auto;rgn1=All+Categories;med=1;view=thumbnail;thsz=12;txsz=50;slsz=1;sstrt=1">thumbnail</A>,
   <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?c=bhl;type=simple;xc=1;q1=auto;rgn1=All+Categories;med=1;view=text;thsz=12;txsz=50;slsz=1;sstrt=1">text</A>,
   or <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?c=bhl;type=simple;xc=1;q1=auto;rgn1=All+Categories;med=1;view=slide;thsz=12;txsz=50;slsz=1;sstrt=1">slideshow</A></LI>
   
   <LI><A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?lasttype=simple;view=entry;subview=detail;cc=bhl;entryid=X-bl000208;viewid=1;sstrt=1;hits=3;q1=auto;rgn1=All+Categories;c=bhl;med=1;xc=1;thsz=12;txsz=50;slsz=1">Full
   record view</A></LI>
   <LI><A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?lasttype=boolean;view=entry;subview=detail;cc=apis;entryid=X-1637;viewid=1;sstrt=1;hits=5;q1=2810;op2=And;op3=And;rgn1=All+Categories;rgn2=All+Categories;rgn3=All+Categories;c=apis;thsz=12;txsz=100;slsz=1">Display of complex image structures</A> (Please scroll through entire page.)</LI>
   <LI><A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?sstrt=1;q1=auto;rgn1=All+Categories;c=bhl;med=1;xc=1;thsz=12;txsz=50;slsz=1;subview=getsid;lasttype=simple;view=entry;viewid=1;entryid=X-bl000208;cc=bhl;ox=1447;oy=294;lastres=1;quality=small;res=1;image.x=266;image.y=202">Zooming
   and panning</A> for image display; integrated into template
   scheme; no special client software needed</LI>
   
   <LI><A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?lasttype=simple;view=entry;subview=detail;cc=blake;entryid=X-1;viewid=1;sstrt=1;hits=54;q1=blake;rgn1=All+Categories;c=blake;med=1;thsz=12;txsz=55;slsz=1">Flipping</A>
   among pages/images associated with a record</LI>
   
   <LI><A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/k/kma/compare.html">Comparison</A>
   of two images from two searches</LI>
   
   <LI>Browsing, either by <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?type=simple;q1=captain;rgn1=All+Categories;c=bhl;med=1;thsz=12;txsz=50;slsz=1;sstrt=1;view=thumb">a
   canned query</A> embedded in a link, or with a the "<A HREF="http://www.picturesofrecord-wired.com/bin/por-idx?page=browseimgframe">word
   wheel</A>." (note that the word wheel is not
   currently an integral component of the Image Class)</LI>
</UL>
</DIV2>


<DIV2 ID="generalparams">
<H2><A NAME="General Parameters"></A>General Parameters</H2>

<P>Campus image collections, such as those found in museums,
libraries, and departments, are spread across campus, and managed
independently and differently. Each collection is unique, from the
nature of the images, to the cataloging methods, to the management
system, and providing public access to catalogs and images requires
an understanding of the similarities and disparities that exist. No
amount of technology will fully resolve the differences among data,
and only an appropriate and practical application of technology and
the sharing of documentation methods, will make a broad service image
access system work well to serve instructional and research needs.
The Image Class federates collections at the point of access in order
to best support the diversity of collections and management
practices.</P>

<P>The Image Class supports descriptive text databases that are built
of structured records and fields. Continuous tone image files are
typically associated with the database, and referenced by filename
data maintained in one of the fields. Within this basic structure
there are many variations. Digital images are actually not a
requirement, though if they are available, they must be continuos
tone. The basic variations are as follows:</P>

<UL>
   <LI>zero digital images per record</LI>
   
   <LI>one digital image per record</LI>
   
   <LI>multiple digital images per record</LI>
</UL>

<TABLE BORDER="1">
<TBODY>
   <TR>
      <TH>
         <P>Images Per Record</P>
      </TH>
      <TH>
         <P>Example</P>
      </TH>
   </TR>
   <TR>
      <TD>
         <P>0</P>
      </TD>
      <TD>
         <P><A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/afroammugroup/"><B>African American Music Collection</B></A></P>
      </TD>
   </TR>
   <TR>
      <TD>
         <P>1</P>
      </TD>
      <TD>
         <P><A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/b/bhl/"><B>Bentley
         Historical Library</B></A></P>
      </TD>
   </TR>
   <TR>
      <TD>
         <P>Multiple</P>
      </TD>
      <TD>
         <P><B>Kelsey Museum of Archaeology - </B><A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/k/kma/"><B>Egyptian
         Amulets</B></A></P>
      </TD>
   </TR>
   <TR>
      <TD>
         <P>Combination</P>
      </TD>
      <TD>
         <P><A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/m/musart/"><B>Museum
         of Art</B></A></P>
      </TD>
   </TR>
</TBODY>
</TABLE>

<P>A database may have any combination of the above. Once deployed in
the Image Class, it is possible to represent each individually in a search
results set, even though they are from a single record. When the record
is viewed, links to all referenced images are displayed. For example,
a <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?type=simple;q1=4110;cat1=All+Categories;med=1;thsz=12;txsz=50;slsz=1;c=kma;sstrt=1;res=thumbnail">search
for "4110"</A> in the Kelsey Amulet collection comes up with 2 results, both from one record.
</P>
<P>It has been discovered through experience with multiple datasets
from internal and external sources that data structures vary only
slightly (as depicted in the table above), but that the content in
the structures varies tremendously. As an example, compare the
<A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry;subview=detail;cc=musart;entryid=X-1895.17;viewid=1">artist</A>
field in the Museum of Art database with the <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry;subview=detail;cc=blake;entryid=X-1;viewid=4">creator</A>
field in William Blake's <I>Songs of Innocence and Experience</I>.
</P>
<P>The disparities are not much of a problem until searching across
databases is attempted. It is a considerable achievement that the
Image Class supports cross-collection searching, and that it does so
without forcing low level normalization of the data. All database
specific fields are available to the user for search and display when
doing a collection specific search. In the cross-collection search
all of the fields are available, but only through a common set of
generalized field mappings (thought of as high level normalization).
For example, a <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?type=simple;view=thumb;sstrt=1;q1=blake;rgn1=Creator;c=blake;c=musart;xc=1;thsz=12;txsz=50;slsz=1">cross-collection
search on a common field</A> called "creator"&#0160;searches the
artist field of the Museum of Art database and the creator field of
the Blake database.
</P>
<P>The Image Class by default uses a basic version of <A HREF="http://purl.oclc.org/dc/">Dublin
Core</A> &#91; <A HREF="http://purl.oclc.org/dc/">http://purl.oclc.org/dc/</A>
&#93;as the set of common fields for cross-collection searching. Any
common set of fields may be used in addition to or in place of Dublin
Core. It is easy to envision the situation where subsets of
collections use core field sets that are suitable to their subject.
For instance, databases from slide libraries might be drawn together
with the <A HREF="http://www.oberlin.edu/~art/vra/core.html">VRA
Core</A> &#91; <A HREF="http://www.oberlin.edu/~art/vra/core.html">http://www.oberlin.edu/~art/vra/core.html</A>
&#93; (Visual Resources Association).</P>

<P>It is possible to represent complex image relationships in the Image Class. For example, a summary image with several additional images as detailed views. Or a matrix of images that together represent something larger. The <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/">Advanced Papyrological Information System</A> makes good use of these features.</P> 

<P>Continuos tone images serve clearly
different purposes than bitonal images. Bitonal images are typically
used for text page images and other high contrast imaging situations
where gradations among the visual elements of the page are not
essential to the intellectual value of the content represented. For
example, in most cases the intellectual value of a typeset page from
a book can be fully captured in a bitonal image. The purpose is met
if the text is readable. A color photograph, however, will typically
lose valuable information if the full range of tones is not captured
in the digital image. Given this, continuos tone images and bitonal
images, need vastly different functionality for viewing by users.
Bitonal images generally need to be flipped like the pages of a book,
and continuos tone images need to be evaluated in a glance for
relevance or inspected at the greatest detail. The generalizations
are obvious, and there are already situations in the Image Class
where continuos tone images are flipped like the pages of a book.
But, the Image Class specializes in serving the most popular uses of
continuos tone images by providing pages of thumbnails for making
sweeping relevance decisions, and powerful panning and zooming
functionality for inspecting the finest details of an image.
</P>
<P>Digital images are retrieved by the unique record identifiers of
the text database, and never by filename. Filenames, moreso than
record identifiers, have potential to change over time. The Image
Class implementation strives to provide reliable, long term, access
to specific records and images.
</P>
<P>The flexibility of the Image Class to assimilate databases and
that same time maintain unique characteristics of each is perhaps
it's greatest strength. The advanced capabilities for viewing
continuous tone images may be just as important. The Image Class
successfully handles databases from a variety of domains including
art, art history, architecture, archaeology, archives, and journals.
The baseline requirement is only that there is some degree of item
level description-- minimally a unique identifier.
</P>
</DIV2>
<DIV2 ID="dynamics">
<H2><A NAME="Dynamics"></A>Dynamics</H2>

<P>The data structure and behaviors of the Image Class best serve the
functional requirements of single images (e.g., photographs), and
multiple images that provide multiple views of single objects (e.g.,
views of a sculpture). Multiple images from a bound manuscript or
illustrated journal are also handled well, especially when a
text-based counterpart exists (e.g., <A HREF="http://www.hti.umich.edu/h/harpersweekly/">Harper's
Weekly</A> &#91; <A HREF="http://www.hti.umich.edu/h/harpersweekly/">http://www.hti.umich.edu/h/harpersweekly/</A>
&#93;). At this time the Image Class has basic functionality for
<A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?lasttype=simple;view=entry;subview=detail;cc=harpersweekly;entryid=X-1865;viewid=1;sstrt=1;hits=836;q1=a;rgn1=All+Categories;c=harpersweekly;med=1;thsz=12;txsz=55;slsz=1">page
flipping</A>, which is more often handled in a text system. If in the
future a considerable amount of content emerges that requires both
continuous tone images and book-like functionality, it may be
sensible to establish a new class to better serve the homogeneity and
distinctiveness of the content in the Image Class and in the spin-off
class.
</P>
<P>Digital video and audio also have potential to stretch the Image
Class in unsuitable ways. The Image Class was actually designed with
the notion that it might some day accommodate video and audio in the
future. It is easy to envision using the Image Class as a starting
place for these media types. It also seems likely that the time-based
characteristics of video and audio would instantiate a new class
based on the existing flexible fielded text searching with added
time-based functionality. Consideration also needs to be given to the
question of whether it is appropriate to search still images, video,
and audio together. Similarly, methods of searching still images by
visual characteristics are evolving and it may soon be desirable to
complement the text searching with such features. This does not
necessarily put a tension on the Image Class as it is, but might
increase the likelihood of splitting away other media types.
</P>

</DIV2>
<DIV2 ID="datadef">
<H2><A NAME="Formal Data Definition"></A>Formal Data Definition</H2>

<DIV3>
<H3><A NAME="Descriptive Metadata (text)"></A>Descriptive Metadata
(text)</H3>

<P>The Image Class relies on a single Standard Generalized Markup Language (SGML)&#0160;<A HREF="image-dtd.xml">Document 
  Type Definition (DTD)</A> to represent all collections in the class. Typically 
  each collection has descriptive text in a database of records and fields. The 
  fielded data is exported from the database to a simple ASCII text format. The 
  fielded data is then encoded with the SGML tags defined by the DTD giving it 
  a clearly defined and parsable structure. The SGML&#0160;is then indexed and 
  made searchable on the Web by the Image Class middleware.</P>

<P>In the <A HREF="#General Parameters">General Parameters</A> section the variety 
  of record to image relationships were described. The structure imposed by the 
  Image Class DTD normalizes these relationships in order to optimize search and 
  retrieval performance. Descriptive data is replicated within the SGML in order 
  to create a 1 to 1 relationship between the descriptive data provided by the 
  original text record and all of the image files associated with the record. 
  The original hierarchical relationship (one record with many images) are maintained 
  through additional tagging and structure that wraps the multiple images together 
  in an itemized fashion. A more detailed breakdown, with examples, is available 
  in the document <A HREF="image-dtd.xml">Image Class DTD Description</A>.</P>

<P>The outstanding strength of the Image Class DTD&#0160;is the way
that it encodes the full set of collection specific data categories
while mapping the categories to a more general set of categories
commonly applied to all collections of the Class. This topic is
covered fully in the <A HREF="#General Parameters">General
Parameters</A> section of this document.</P>
</DIV3>
<DIV3>
<H3><A NAME="Image Data"></A>Image Data</H3>

<P>The Image data in the Image Class is continous tone, most often
meaning 24-bits of color or 8-bits of grayscale pixel data.</P>

<P>Thumbnail size images used in the display of search results are
stored on the server as static JPEG&#0160;(JFIF&#0160;format with lossy
JPEG compression) files. The GIF format is also supported.</P>

<P>The larger, display, version of an image may be stored on the
server as a static JPEG (JFIF format with lossy JPEG compression)
file in two resolutions (large and medium), or in a SID&#0160;format (<A HREF="http://www.lizardtech.com">LizardTech's
MrSID</A> &#91; <A HREF="http://www.lizardtech.com">http://www.lizardtech.com</A>
&#93; format with lossy wavelet compression) file with multiple
levels of resolution inherently available through the compression
scheme. The SID format is a far superior option with compression
ratios of 20 to 1 easily achieved with minimal image degradation and
multiple resolutions by default. Since the SID format is not
supported internally by web browsers, the Image Class middleware
extracts image data from the SID format on the fly and delivers it to
the browser in the JPEG format. MrSID allows the extraction of any
portion of any predefined resolution level from an image, enabling
panning, zooming, and cropping functionality in the user interface.
</P>
</DIV3>
</DIV2>
<DIV2 ID="resources">
<H2><A NAME="Representative Resource(s)"></A>Representative
Resource(s)</H2>

<P>The University of Michigan, Museum of Art, The Kelsey Museum of
Archaeology's Registry Database, and William Blake's <I>Songs of
Innocence and Experience</I> are resources implemented in the Image
Class that represent well the depth and breadth of intended use.</P>

<P><A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/m/musart/">The University of
Michigan, Museum of Art</A><BR/>
&#91; <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/m/musart/">http://images.umdl.umich.edu/m/musart/</A>
&#93;</P>

<P>A comprehensive and growing catalog of the Museum's holdings, the
implementation of this database in the Image Class is the best all
around example. There are over 12,000 text records, and over 10,000
digital images. Most records have <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?type=detail;cc=musart;entryid=X-1935.28;viewid=1;sstrt=2;hits=448;q1=water;cat1=All%20Categories;thsz=12;txsz=50;slsz=1;c=musart">one
digital image</A>, some records have <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?type=detail;cc=musart;entryid=X-1942.6;viewid=2;sstrt=2;hits=10;q1=processional%20cross;cat1=All%20Categories;thsz=12;txsz=50;slsz=1;c=musart">multiple
images</A>, and a far smaller number do not yet have digital images.
In the mid-1990's the Museum photographed and digitized the entire
collection. At the same time they migrated their collection
management database to the DCI&#0160;Embark system. The Embark system
provides good internal management functionality for curators,
including the ability to view the digital images. Image Services
provides public access to the collection via the Image Class. The
digital images provided by the Museum are of very high quality and
make good use of the advanced image viewing functionality of the
Class. The Museum of Art data is updated about three times a year,
but as often as monthly. Additionally, it is worth noting that the
Museum restricts access outside of the University to some large
versions of images due to copyright restrictions.</P>

<P><A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/k/kelsey/">The Kelsey Museum
of Archaeology's Registry Database</A><BR/>
&#91; <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/k/kelsey/">http://images.umdl.umich.edu/k/kelsey/</A>
&#93;</P>

<P>The Kelsey manages a database of over 90,000 records that
describes the physical artifacts held by the museum. Currently there
are <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?type=detail;cc=kelsey;entryid=X-0000.00.0001;viewid=1;sstrt=1;hits=3561;q1=lamp;cat1=All%20Categories;txsz=50;slsz=1;c=kelsey">about 200
digital images</A> associated with the database. The Kelsey uses
FileMaker Pro, setup with a relational structure that includes
several tables. Previous to providing public access through Image
Services, the Kelsey provided restricted access to the database with
FileMaker's database sharing capabilities on an under powered
Macintosh. The database is now available to the world through the
Image Class. The Kelsey database is updated in the Image Class
quarterly. Recently 200 images were digitized by Image Services. The
images are the primary images used by two UM&#0160;courses, and are available in conjunction with the Kelseyt entity entity's Registry Database.
</P>
<P><A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/b/blake/">William Blake's
<I>Songs of Innocence and Experience</I></A><I><BR/>
</I>&#91; <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/b/blake/">http://images.umdl.umich.edu/b/blake/</A>
&#93;</P>

<P>Blake's <I>Songs</I> is an illustrated manuscript that is
preferably accessed by <A HREF="http://www.hti.umich.edu/b/blake/">searching
the full text</A>. The digital images are color, and of high enough
quality to merit use of the Image Class advanced image viewing
functionality. Blake's <I>Songs</I>, implemented as a "collection" in
the Image Class, has only <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?type=detail;cc=blake;entryid=X-1;viewid=1;sstrt=1;hits=54;q1=blake;cat1=All%20Categories;thsz=12;txsz=55;slsz=1;med=1;c=blake">one
bibliographic-like record</A> with all of the manuscript's images associated with it. The record
also has descriptive title's for each image, taken from the text of
each page. It is valuable to have Blake's Songs in the Image Class so
that users searching across collections have an opportunity to
discover the illustrated manuscript pages along with works by Blake
in other collections. Furthermore, the searchable text which is
online on a separate machine in a separate system, has links to the
images in the Image Class, and vice-versa. The links are handled by
the DLPS&#0160;ID Resolver, which is a simple mechanism for resolving
a unique identifier into a URL. This interoperability provides the
user with the best functions for viewing images and the best
functions for retrieving text, and delegates functionality in an
appropriate manner.
</P>
<P>The decision process for inclusion of content in the Image Class
is roughly based on the following:
</P>
<UL>
   <LI>Digital images are, or potentially would be in cases where
   digital images are not yet available, continuous tone (i.e., color
   or grayscale)</LI>
   
   <LI>Descriptive text is structured in fields, such as in a
   database</LI>
   
   <LI>The database describes, directly in the case of museums, or
   indirectly in the case of visual resources collections, images,
   objects, artifacts, or specimens, that contain visual
   information.</LI>
   
   <LI>The campus and/or world community would benefit from access to
   the information.</LI>
</UL>

<P>These are, at best, general guidelines for decision making based
on the current state of the Image Class implementation at the
University of Michigan. There is plenty of room to diversify the
content, or deploy additional instantiations of the Class to serve
another content area.
</P>



<P>jweise@umich.edu</P>

</DIV2>
</DIV1>
</BODY>
</DLPSDOC>
