<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!-- SPO Editorial Services                  -->
<!-- automatically-generated XML header file -->

<?xml-stylesheet href="../../../pre11-dlxsdocs.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE DLPSDOC PUBLIC "-//UM-DLPS//DTD DLPS Publications//EN" "http://docs.umdl.umich.edu/dlps/docs/dlpsdocs.dtd">
<DLPSDOC>
<TITLE>Image Class Data Requirements</TITLE>
<HEADER>
<JOURNAL>DLXS Documentation</JOURNAL>
<PUBDATE>2003-12-01 11:19:27 EST</PUBDATE>
<AUTH1>Weise, John</AUTH1>
<AUTH2></AUTH2>
<DOCTITLE>Image Class Data Requirements</DOCTITLE>
<VOL>class</VOL>
<ISS>image</ISS>
<FILE>dlxsdocs-image-datareqs</FILE>
</HEADER>


<BODY>
<BHEAD>Image Class Data Requirements</BHEAD>
<DIV1 ID="main">

<P>
<A HREF="mailto:dlxs-help@umich.edu">dlxs-help@umich.edu</A>
</P>


<P>Each collection used in the Image Services system must have a
unique abbreviation. The abbreviation is used in many places in the
system.</P>

<P>Examples:</P>

<TABLE BORDER="1">
<TBODY>
   <TR>
      <TD>
         <P>Unique (across all classes) collection abbreviation (lowercase alphabetic
         characters, only)</P>
      </TD>
      <TD>
         <P>Long collection name</P>
      </TD>
   </TR>
   <TR>
      <TD>
         <P>musart</P>
      </TD>
      <TD>
         <P>Museum of Art</P>
      </TD>
   </TR>
   <TR>
      <TD>
         <P>scl</P>
      </TD>
      <TD>
         <P>Special Collections Library</P>
      </TD>
   </TR>
   <TR>
      <TD>
         <P>sampleic</P>
      </TD>
      <TD>
         <P>French Architecture</P>
      </TD>
   </TR>
</TBODY>
</TABLE>

<P>Each record must minimally have fields of the following
<B>type</B>:</P>

<TABLE BORDER="1">
<TBODY>
   <TR>
      <TD>
         <P>Identifier</P>
      </TD>
      <TD>
         <P>Unique identification of the record within the collection</P>
      </TD>
   </TR>
   <TR>
      <TD>
         <P>Image Filename(s)</P>
      </TD>
      <TD>
         <P>The image filename including (master) filename extension. This may
         be a repeating field. (Not required if there are no images)</P>
      </TD>
   </TR>
   <TR>
      <TD>
         <P>Image Caption(s)</P>
      </TD>
      <TD>
         <P>Describes the specific view depicted in the image file.
         If the Image Filename field is repeating, then the Image
         Caption field(s) may be repeating also (though it is not a requirement). There may be
         multiple image caption fields. In many cases, and especially
         when there is only one image file per record, many or all of
         the fields of the record might be considered
         "caption"&#0160;fields. In such a case it usually works best
         to consider only the fields that describe the view depicted
         in the image to be caption fields. For example, a good
         caption field would be one that has data similar to "view
         from the south"&#0160;or "verso"&#0160;or "aerial view".</P>
      </TD>
   </TR>
</TBODY>
</TABLE>

<P>Remember, this document is about minimal requirements. Please read <A HREF="image-imagestructures.xml">Image Class - Mapping Image Structures</A> for full coverage of image file topics.</P>

<DIV2 ID="identifiers">
<H2>Identifiers</H2>

<P>Requirements for identifiers loosened up with DLXS 10. 
The Image Class DTD was changed to allow a wider range of characters in IDs.
Previously there were significant limitations on
the characters that are allowed within SGML IDs. Unique record IDs in
image databases can take many different forms and include many
different characters. Even though a wider range of chanracters are allowed, 
the provided script ("idb") for preparing Image Class data continues
to filter illegal SGML ID characters into legal logical
representations of the character in order to ensure legal SGML IDs. 
This practice has continued in order to maintain backward compatability for
databases that pre-existed the change.</P>
<P>Image Class uses the right square bracket "]" as a delimeter within ids
which are a concatenation of the record ID and the image filename (when present).
Other use of the square bracket in IDs and filenames is therefore problematic.
</P>
</DIV2>
<DIV2 ID="images">
<H2>About Images</H2>

<P>A database does not have to have digital images associated with
it. It is acceptable for a database to not have an Image Filename
field.</P>

<P>Any given record in a database may have 0, 1 or multiple image
files associated with it.</P> 



</DIV2>
<DIV2 ID="otherfields">
<H2>Other Fields</H2>

<P>Typically there are many other fields in a database. This is allowed.</P>
</DIV2>
<DIV2 ID="fieldsnames">
<H2>Field Names</H2>

<P>Each field is given an abbreviation and label in Image Class. The abbreviation must be a legal MySQL field name. 
The label can contain ASCII Latin 1 characters.</P>
</DIV2>
<DIV2 ID="multipleuses">
<H2>Multiple Uses</H2>

<P>In some cases a field has potential to serve multiple
requirements. In the most extreme example, a database might have just
one field, "ID". The ID might also be the Image Filename, and the
Image Caption. Of course this would not likely be very useful for
searching, but it makes the point. The more common example is where
image files are named by accession number. It is acceptable for a
single field to serve more than one of the minimal field
requirements, however it is absolutely critical for there to be no
ambiguity in the use of the field for multiple purposes. For example,
if data in an accession number field are to be used for filenames as
well, then the actual image files must be named exactly as the
accession numbers. Use of IDs as filenames is becoming less feasible as 
Image Class gains support for new media formats. It is a good idea to have separate ID and image filename fields, and theimage filenames should include extensions. The extension should match the master image file format, which may be different than the format used on the server.</P>
</DIV2>
<DIV2 ID="charactersets">
<H2><A HREF="image-charconversion.xml">Character Sets</A></H2>

<P>All characters in the database must be 8-bit ISO
8859 Latin 1 characters. For some collections this may be rather
restrictive. At this time, characters that are not compliant
with the standard will be converted to "?" (a question mark character)
	  and not searchable properly. They also will not
display properly (the question mark character will display as a place holder). Some characters may slip through the filters and generate errors at the time of SGML validation, though in most cases the errors may be
ignored with the understanding that search, retrieval and display
will be affected. Sometime your only choice is to ignore the errors if it is not possible to determine what the appropriate character should be.</P>
</DIV2>
</DIV1>
</BODY>
</DLPSDOC>
