<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!-- SPO Editorial Services                  -->
<!-- automatically-generated XML header file -->

<?xml-stylesheet href="../../../pre11-dlxsdocs.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE DLPSDOC PUBLIC "-//UM-DLPS//DTD DLPS Publications//EN" "http://docs.umdl.umich.edu/dlps/docs/dlpsdocs.dtd">
<DLPSDOC>
<TITLE>Image Class COLLDB (Collection Database)</TITLE>
<HEADER>
<JOURNAL>DLXS Documentation</JOURNAL>
<PUBDATE>2003-12-01 11:16:46 EST</PUBDATE>
<AUTH1>Weise, John</AUTH1>
<AUTH2></AUTH2>
<DOCTITLE>Image Class COLLDB (Collection Database)</DOCTITLE>
<VOL>class</VOL>
<ISS>image</ISS>
<FILE>dlxsdocs-image-colldb</FILE>
</HEADER>


<BODY> <BHEAD>Image Class COLLDB (Collection Database) Configuration</BHEAD> 
<DIV1 ID="main">

  <DIV2 ID="table">
  
<P>The COLLDB (collection database) is for configuration of individual collections. 
  Many aspects of how a collection is presented in the interface are controlled 
  by elements in the COLLDB. It is very powerful in that sense, and allows extensive 
  customization to be done without creation of HTML templates. It is still possible 
  to create templates and modify style sheets, etc. if that is necessary. Please 
  see <A href="../../ui/dlxs-templates.xml">DLXS HTML Templates / Interfaces</A> for an overview.</P>
<P>Some of the COLLDB elements may have corresponding Processing Instructions. Under 
  certain situations, the Processing Instruction may override the COLLDB. This 
  generally happens in a logical fashion. Just be aware of this possibility.</P>
  <P><STRONG>The majority of Collmgr Fields are fully documented within Collmgr.
  This document now only includes extensive information beyond what could be reasonably kept in the Collmgr help document.
  </STRONG>
  </P>
  
  
<H2>Table of COLLDB Field Definitions</H2>
<table border="1" cellpadding="5" cellspacing="1" width="95%">
  <TBODY> 
  <tr> 
    <th width="*"> Field Name </th>
    <th width="*"> Description </th>
    <th width="*">Example</th>
  </tr>

<tr valign="top"> 
    <td width="*"><strong>dfltentryflds</strong> and <strong>dfltresentryflds</strong></td>
    <td width="*">the list of fields (as abbreviations) to display in entry (full 
      record) views. to display all fields, enter the value &quot;default&quot;.</td>
    <td width="*"> 
      <div align="left">
        <p>BHL_IT<BR/>BHL_TIS<BR/>dateconv:on<BR/>BHL_DA<BR/>dateconv:off<BR/>BHL_CR<BR/>BHL_WC<BR/>BHL_CA<BR/>BHL_NO<BR/>BHL_SU<BR/>BHL_G<BR/>BHL_CT<BR/>
          BHL_CC<BR/>BHL_LO<BR/>BHL_ITNO<BR/>BHL_NE<BR/>BHL_SS<BR/>url:on<BR/>idres:on<BR/>BHL_EL<BR/>url:off<BR/>idres:off<BR/>BHL_RI<BR/>BHL_RE</p>
        <p>In colldb, values must be listed 1 per line. However within a processing instruction, values must be delimited 
          by pipes ( &quot;|&quot; ). e.g., MUSART.TI|MUSART.CR|musart.DA</p>
        <p>Values are not case sensitive. </p>
        <p>There are several options that may be turned on and off to enhance 
          the display of records. The options are specified as another value among 
          abbreviations. When the status of an option is changed, the change is 
          persistent for all subsequent fields, until the status is changed again. 
          The exceptions to this are &quot;sectionlabel&quot; and &quot;urltext&quot;, 
          which are specified as often as needed.</p>
        <p>The &quot;url&quot; option, for example, causes fields that contain 
          a URL (and nothing but a URL), to be turned into a hyperlink. It can 
          be used in conjunction with the &quot;urltext&quot; option, which 
          allows the link text to be specified. By default the URL itself is used 
          for the link text. e.g., <br/>
          MUSART.TI<BR/>url:on<BR/>urltext:View_Copyright_Statement<BR/>MUSART.cp<BR/>url:off<BR/>MUSART.DA</p>
        <p>The &quot;hilite&quot; option causes search terms to be hilited. This 
          option is &quot;on&quot; by default, but if you wanted to turn hiliting 
          off for several consecutive fields, you could. e.g., MUSART.TI<BR/>hilite:off<BR/>MUSART.DA<BR/>MUSART.PG<BR/>MUSART.LI<BR/>hilite:on<BR/>MUSART.TY</p>
        <p>The complete list of field options are as follows: </p>
        <table width="100%" border="1" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="1">
          <tr> 
            <th width="14%">option</th>
            <th width="31%">values</th>
            <th width="7%">default</th>
            <th width="48%">description</th>
          </tr>
          <tr> 
            <td width="14%">label</td>
            <td width="31%">on/off</td>
            <td width="7%">on</td>
            <td width="48%">display name of field before field value</td>
          </tr>
          <tr> 
            <td width="14%" height="37">sectionlabel</td>
            <td width="31%" height="37">text string*<br/>
            </td>
            <td width="7%" height="37">empty</td>
            <td width="48%" height="37">display a section label before a series 
              of fields. allows a record to split into sections.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr> 
            <td width="14%">url</td>
            <td width="31%">on/off</td>
            <td width="7%">off</td>
            <td width="48%">turn the entire contents of the field in to a link. 
              assumes the field contains a single URL.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr> 
            <td width="14%">urltext</td>
            <td width="31%">text string*</td>
            <td width="7%">empty</td>
            <td width="48%">display the provided string as the text of the &quot;url&quot; 
              option link. if &quot;urltext&quot; is not specified, the URL value 
              is used as the text of the link.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr> 
            <td width="14%">idres</td>
            <td width="31%">on/off</td>
            <td width="7%">off</td>
            <td width="48%">look the value of the field up in the id resolver 
              and display the value. use with &quot;url&quot; and/or &quot;urltext&quot; 
              to turn the value in to a link.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr> 
            <td width="14%">dateconv</td>
            <td width="31%">on/off</td>
            <td width="7%">off</td>
            <td width="48%"> 
              <p>displays some ISO format dates in a more human readable form.</p>
              <p>supports YYYYMMDD, YYYYMMDD/YYYYMMDD and maintains any data that 
                might follow the date in the field e.g, (ca.)</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr> 
            <td width="14%">hilite</td>
            <td width="31%">on/off</td>
            <td width="7%">on</td>
            <td width="48%"> 
              <p>hilites search terms in the field. </p>
              <p>DLXS hiliting supports 3 search fields only (q1 - q3). </p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr> 
            <td width="14%">keylinks</td>
            <td width="31%">on/off</td>
            <td width="7%">off</td>
            <td width="48%"> 
              <p>turns the field value into a url that will search the collection for that value. by default, each word of the field is made into a separate link. the delimiter used to split the field can be specified by the "delim" option.</p>
            </td>
          </tr>

          <tr> 
            <td width="14%">delim</td>
            <td width="31%">1 or more characters</td>
            <td width="7%">SPACE</td>
            <td width="48%"> 
              <p>used in conjunction with the keylinks option to split the value of a field into smaller parts by the value delim specifies. for example, if a field holds a list of keywords delimited by "; " delim can be set to ";_" to tell the keylinks option how to split the field. (note: use an underscore for SPACE.)  e.g., delim:;_</p>
            </td>
          </tr>


        </table>
        <p>* use underscores for spaces. special characters may not work.</p>
        <p>The Processing Instruction &quot;RECORDTABLE&quot; has similar functionality.</p>
      </div>
    </td>
  </tr>


  </TBODY> 
</table>
</DIV2>
</DIV1>

</BODY>

</DLPSDOC>
