<?xml version="1.0"?>
  <!-- SPO Editorial Services                  -->
  <!-- automatically-generated XML header file -->
  
  <?xml-stylesheet href="http://docs.umdl.umich.edu/docs.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
  <!DOCTYPE DLPSDOC PUBLIC "-//UM-DLPS//DTD DLPS Publications//EN" "http://docs.umdl.umich.edu/dlps/docs/dlpsdocs.dtd">
  <DLPSDOC> 
    <TITLE>Image Class Data Loading: MySQL</TITLE>
    <HEADER> 
      <JOURNAL>DLXS Documentation</JOURNAL>
      <PUBDATE>2003-12-01 11:20:19 EST</PUBDATE>
      <AUTH1>Weise, John</AUTH1>
      <AUTH2></AUTH2>
      <DOCTITLE>Image Class Data Loading: MySQL</DOCTITLE>
      <VOL>class</VOL>
      <ISS>image</ISS>
      <FILE>dlxsdocs-image-mysql</FILE>
    </HEADER>
    <BODY> 
      <BHEAD>Image Class Data Loading: MySQL</BHEAD>
      <DIV1> 
        <DIV2 ID="Requirements"> 
          <H2> 
            <A NAME="Requirements"></A>
            Requirements</H2>
          <UL> 
            <LI>MySQL 3.23 or newer. MySQL 4.0.2 or newer is recommended for best 
              searching functionality. Image Class uses the full text search capabilities 
              of MySQL. MySQL version 3.23 has basic full text capability. Version 
              4.02 introduced several new features such as phrase searching, stemming 
              with wildcard, and better boolean controls.</LI>
			  <LI>Using MySQL for Image Class content requires that MySQL also be used for the CollMgr Collection Database.</LI>
			  <LI>Also see: <A HREF="../../intro/dlxs-sysreq.xml">DLXS System Requirements</A></LI>
          </UL>
        </DIV2>
        <DIV2 ID="Introduction"> 
          <H2> 
            <A NAME="Introduction"></A>
            Introduction</H2>
          <P>Image Class version 3 (<A HREF="http://www.dlxs.org">DLXS</A> 11) introduces the use of MySQL for search 
            and retrieval. Assuming DLXS has been installed and tested, the basic 
            steps to bringing a collection online with Image Class and MySQL are 
            as follows.</P>
          <OL> 
            <LI><A HREF="image-imageloading.xml">load image/media files</A> to server, including the running of imageprep.</LI>
            <LI>import descriptive metadata into MySQL as an Image Class Data 
              Table.</LI>
            <LI>import media file metadata into MySQL as an Image Class Media 
              Table (sometimes optional).</LI>
            <LI>use collmgr to create the colldb record for the collection and 
              configure the collection for use. Documentation is
provided contextually within Collmgr.</LI>
            <LI>test in browser.</LI>
          </OL>
          <P> 
            <STRONG>Note:</STRONG>
            <A HREF="image-accesstable.xml">Access restrictions</A> for the collection must also be
established / configured. </P>
        </DIV2>
        <DIV2 ID="DataTable"> 
          <H2> 
            <A NAME="DataTable"></A>
            Data Table</H2>
          <P>A Data Table is required for each collection. The Data Table holds 
            descriptive metadata. A collection can have any number of descriptive 
            metadata fields, and for each there is a column in the Data Table.</P>
          <P>Field names must be legal MySQL field names, otherwise there are 
            no restrictions. </P>
          <P>The Data Table must have a field with unique values that can be used 
            as record identifiers.</P>
          <P>A media filename field is necessary if image files or other types 
            of media are to be displayed by Image Class. Filenames must have filename 
            extensions. It is best if the filename extension matches that of the 
            master image file, and not that of the file to be delivered online. 
            Sometimes they do not differ.</P>
          <P>If searching of the entire record at once is desired, an additional 
            field concatenating the values of all other fields is needed. This 
            is referred to as the "all" field.</P>
          <P>The ID field must have a full text index.</P>
          <P>Each additional field to be searchable in Image Class must have a 
            full text index.</P>
        </DIV2>
        <DIV2 ID="MediaTable"> 
          <H2> 
            <A NAME="Media Table"></A>
            Media Table</H2>
          <P>A collection may require a Media Table. The Media Table contains 
            detailed information about the media files ( i.e., most often images 
            ) that are part of a collection.</P>
          <P>In contrast to the Data Table, the Media Table has a required set 
            of fields that do not vary.</P>
          <P>A Media Table is required in the following situations: </P>
          <UL> 
            <LI>A collection includes multiple media file formats. e.g., any collection simultaneously using sid and jp2 files will need a media table.</LI>
            <LI>A collection includes multiple media files per metadata record.</LI>
			<LI>Some records of a collection do not have media files.</LI>
            
            <LI>Some images of the collection need to be restricted, while others 
              not.</LI>
          </UL>
		  <P><STRONG>Note:</STRONG> The m_id and m_iid fields of the Media Table should be indexed. 
              A full text index is not necessary.</P>
          <P>View the detailed <A HREF="image-mediatable.xml">Media Table Definition</A>.</P>
        </DIV2>
        <DIV2 ID="TableNamingConventions"> 
          <H2> 
            <A NAME="Table Naming Conventions"></A>
            Table Naming Conventions</H2>
          <P>It is recommended that Data and Media Table names relate to the collection 
            ID. Name the Data Table exactly as the collid, and the Media Table 
            as "collid_media". Attaching a simple version number to each will 
            facilitate deployment and minimize interruption of service. </P>
          <P> Initially,</P>
          <UL> 
            <LI>collid_1</LI>
            <LI>collid_media_1</LI>
          </UL>
          <P>and at the next data update, </P> 
           <UL>
            <LI>collid_2 </LI>
            <LI>collid_media_2 </LI></UL> 
          <P>The table names are stored in each collection's Collmgr Collection 
            Database record. Therefore, the tables are not used by Image Class 
            until the Collmgr record is updated and released. This facilitates 
            switching from the old version to the new.</P>
        </DIV2>
        <DIV2 ID="FieldNamingConventions"> 
          <H2> 
            <A NAME="Field Naming Conventions"></A>
            Field Naming Conventions</H2>
          <P>Field labels, as displayed to the end-user in Image Class are easily 
            changed on a whim using Collmgr. Field names, on the other hand, are 
            used behind the scenes for unique identification of fields.</P>
          <P>Image Class has traditionally relied on abbreviated field names that 
            follow the convention collid_fieldabbrev, e.g,. bhl_ti for the Title 
            field of the Bentley Image Bank collection. There is nothing 
            requiring this convention be followed. There is merit in using brief 
            field names since they are carried around on the URL, entered multiple 
            times in the Collmgr Collection Database record, and stored on the 
            CGI session.</P>
          <P>Field names must be legal MySQL field names.</P>
        </DIV2>
        <DIV2 ID="BasicMySQLCommands"> 
          <H2> 
            <A NAME="Basic MySQL Commands"></A>
            Basic MySQL Commands</H2>
          <P>Please refer to MySQL documentation at <A HREF="http://www.mysql.com">www.mysql.com</A> for full instruction 
            on how to use the following MySQL commands on the MySQL command line.</P>
          <P> <HR />Command: 
            <STRONG>show</STRONG>
            <BR></BR>
            Purpose: 
            <STRONG>list existing tables</STRONG>
            <BR></BR>
            Example: </P>
          <CODE>show tables;</CODE>
          <P><HR />Command: 
            <STRONG>create</STRONG>
            <BR></BR>
            Purpose: 
            <STRONG>creating a new table</STRONG>
            <BR></BR>
            Example (using the collection id "art" using the conventions above):</P>
          <CODE>create table ( art_id varchar(10), art_fn varchar(12), art_ti 
            text, art_cr text, art_su text, art_all text ) TYPE=MyISAM;</CODE>
          <P><HR />Command: 
            <STRONG>describe</STRONG>
            <BR></BR>
            Purpose: 
            <STRONG>show the field definitions for a table</STRONG>
            <BR></BR>
            Example: </P>
          <CODE>describe art;</CODE>
          <P><HR />Command: 
            <STRONG>drop</STRONG>
            <BR></BR>
            Purpose: 
            <STRONG>drop/delete a table</STRONG>
            <BR></BR>
            Example:</P>
          <CODE>drop table art;</CODE>
          <P><HR />Command: 
            <STRONG>load</STRONG>
            <BR></BR>
            Purpose: 
            <STRONG>load tab delimited ascii data into table</STRONG>
            <BR></BR>
            See also MySQL documentation: 
            <STRONG>mysqlimport</STRONG>
            <BR></BR>
            Example:</P>
          <CODE>load data local infile 'art.txt' into table art;</CODE>
          <P><HR />Command: 
            <STRONG>select</STRONG>
            <BR></BR>
            Purpose: 
            <STRONG>submit query and display results</STRONG>
            <BR></BR>
            Examples: </P>
          <CODE>select count(*) from table art;
		  select art_ti, art_cr from table 
            art limit 10;
			<BR />
			select art_ti, art_cr from table art where art_cr = 
            "picasso";</CODE>
          <P><HR />Command: 
            <STRONG>alter</STRONG>
            <BR></BR>
            Purpose: 
            <STRONG>adding an index to a field</STRONG>
            <BR></BR>
            Examples: </P>
          <CODE>alter table art add FULLTEXT art_all (art_all); 
		  <BR />alter table art 
            add index art_id (art_id(10));</CODE>
          <P><HR />Command: 
            <STRONG>show</STRONG>
            <BR />
            Purpose: 
            <STRONG>show definitions of database components</STRONG>
            <BR />
            Example:</P>
          <CODE>show create table art;</CODE>
        </DIV2>
      </DIV1>
    </BODY>
  </DLPSDOC>
