<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!-- SPO Editorial Services                  -->
<!-- automatically-generated XML header file -->

<?xml-stylesheet href="../../../pre11-dlxsdocs.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE DLPSDOC PUBLIC "-//UM-DLPS//DTD DLPS Publications//EN" "http://docs.umdl.umich.edu/dlps/docs/dlpsdocs.dtd">
<DLPSDOC>
<TITLE>Making Changes to the Text Class Middleware</TITLE>
<HEADER>
<JOURNAL>DLXS Documentation</JOURNAL>
<PUBDATE>2002-03-13 11:54:23 EST</PUBDATE>
<AUTH1>Pagliere, Alan</AUTH1>
<AUTH2></AUTH2>
<DOCTITLE>Making Changes to the Text Class Middleware</DOCTITLE>
<VOL>class</VOL>
<ISS>text</ISS>
<FILE>dlxsdocs-tc-changingmiddleware</FILE>
</HEADER>

<BODY>
<BHEAD>Making Changes to the DLXS Text Class Middleware</BHEAD>

<DIV1><H1>OVERVIEW</H1>
<P>Since there is much generic code in the TextClass middleware, little must
be done to add a new collection. Following are the basic steps and who is
usually responsible for them:</P>
<TABLE BORDER="1">
<TBODY>
<TR>
<TD>Conversion to the delivery DTD</TD>
<TD>Content Specialist</TD>
</TR>
<TR>
<TD>Indexing and creation of any needed fabricated regions</TD>
<TD>Content Specialist</TD>
</TR>
<TR>
<TD>Editing of the new collection's mapper file</TD>
<TD>Content Specialist</TD>
</TR>
<TR>
<TD>Addition to the colldb of appropriate collection specific
metadata</TD>
<TD>Content Specialist</TD>
</TR>
<TR>
<TD>Addition of collection to those authorized</TD>
<TD>System Admin or Programmer</TD>
</TR></TBODY>
</TABLE>

<P>This alone should be enough to get the collection online if the
collection is made to use the TextClass.pm generic module.</P>
<P>If some
collection specific characteristics or behavior are required, such as a
difference in the depth of DIVs, or specific searching or filtering, then
subclassing of the TextClass module will be necessary, which of course is
usually done by the Programmer.</P>
</DIV1>
<DIV1><H1>SUBCLASSING THE TEXTCLASS</H1>
<P>It is often a good idea to copy a TextClass subclass module and make
changes to it. A convention has evolved at DLPS to name subclass modules
something like <I>Coll</I>TC.pm, where <I>Coll </I>is an identifier for the
collection. The <TT>_initialize</TT> method
should call the superclass's method and then override whatever it needs to.
Often this is nothing more than declaring the hashes that control the depth of
DIVs and other elements for searching and filtering.</P>
</DIV1>
<DIV1><H1>SEARCHING AND FILTERING</H1>
<P>Sometimes specific searching, but more often, specific filtering is
necessary. In this case, overriding any methods and subroutines necessary in the
TextClass.pm superclass module can be done in the CollTC subclass module.</P>
</DIV1>
</BODY>
</DLPSDOC>
