<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!-- SPO Editorial Services                  -->
<!-- automatically-generated XML header file -->

<?xml-stylesheet href="../../../pre11-dlxsdocs.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE DLPSDOC PUBLIC "-//UM-DLPS//DTD DLPS Publications//EN" "http://docs.umdl.umich.edu/dlps/docs/dlpsdocs.dtd">
<DLPSDOC>
<TITLE>Text Class General Page Layout and Color</TITLE>
<HEADER>
<JOURNAL>DLXS Documentation</JOURNAL>
<PUBDATE>2002-07-08 11:48:29 EDT</PUBDATE>
<AUTH1>Stoeffler, Matt</AUTH1>
<AUTH2></AUTH2>
<DOCTITLE>Text Class General Page Layout and Color</DOCTITLE>
<VOL>class</VOL>
<ISS>text</ISS>
<FILE>dlxsdocs-tc-gen-pg-layout</FILE>
</HEADER>
<BODY>
    <BHEAD>Text Class General Page Layout and Color</BHEAD>
 
<DIV1 ID="main"> 
  
<P>Default page delivery in Text Class is done via "class-level" templates that are shared 
  by all instances of the class, though the middleware also supports "collection-specific" 
  templates for any or all collections to implement collection-specific behavior. All default Text 
  Class page templates are based on the same layout approach, which relies on 
  tables (along with transparent spacer gifs) for all positioning and general 
  color or graphic appearance. General layout is shown in <B>Figure 1</B>, which 
  shows top-level tables with borders showing, and using the color scheme for 
  the <A HREF="http://ets.umdl.umich.edu/v/voltaire/">Voltaire &#x00e9;lectroniqu</A>e collection. All table cells for header and 
  navigation bar content at this level have default values for the <CODE>bgcolor</CODE> 
  attribute for browsers that are not CSS-capable. Each header and navigation 
  cell also has a default CSS class value and default background image specified 
  in the <CODE>background</CODE> attribute. The background colors created by class 
  and gif allow for flexibility to change appearances for different collections 
  based on the same template. For more on specifiying individual collection appearance, 
  see <A HREF="tc-ind-coll-chars.xml">Specifying individual collection characteristics</A>.</P>
  <TABLE BORDER="0" CELLSPACING="2" CELLPADDING="0">
    <TR>
      <TD><IMG SRC="graphics/gen-layout.gif" WIDTH="450" HEIGHT="368"/></TD>
    </TR>
    <TR>
      <TD><B>Figure 1</B>: top-level tables with borders showing.</TD>
    </TR>
  </TABLE>
<BR/>
  <P><B> Figure 2</B> shows the simple search page for Voltaire &#x00e9;lectronique 
    as it appears normally. Navigation bar labels, page header (i.e., &quot;Simple 
    search&quot;), instruction text and footer text are hard coded, and thus identical 
    across all collections. All other content is specified per collection by processing 
    instructions which, when precessed by the CGI, are replaced with collection-specific content, usually from the DLXS collection information database. </P>
  <TABLE BORDER="0" CELLSPACING="2" CELLPADDING="0">
    <TR>
      <TD><IMG SRC="graphics/simple-voltaire-450.gif" WIDTH="449" HEIGHT="289" BORDER="1"/></TD>
    </TR>
    <TR>
      <TD><B>Figure 2</B>: simple search page for Voltaire &#x00e9;lectronique.</TD>
    </TR>
  </TABLE>
<BR/><BR/><BR/>
</DIV1>
  </BODY>
</DLPSDOC>
