<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!-- SPO Editorial Services                  -->
<!-- automatically-generated XML header file -->

<?xml-stylesheet href="../../../pre11-dlxsdocs.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE DLPSDOC PUBLIC "-//UM-DLPS//DTD DLPS Publications//EN" "http://docs.umdl.umich.edu/dlps/docs/dlpsdocs.dtd">
<DLPSDOC>
<TITLE>Guidelines for Mapping to Core Categories for Image Services</TITLE>
<HEADER>
<JOURNAL>DLXS Documentation</JOURNAL>
<PUBDATE>2002-07-03 17:11:04 EDT</PUBDATE>
<AUTH1>Weise, John</AUTH1>
<AUTH2></AUTH2>
<DOCTITLE>Guidelines for Mapping to Core Categories for Image Services</DOCTITLE>
<VOL>class</VOL>
<ISS>image</ISS>
<FILE>dlxsdocs-image-dc-guidelines</FILE>
</HEADER>




<BODY>
<BHEAD>Guidelines for Mapping to Core Categories for Image Services</BHEAD>
<DIV1 ID="main">

<P><A HREF="mailto:dlxs-help@umich.edu">dlxs-help@umich.edu</A>
</P>

<P>
<B>Disclaimer:</B> <I>The
   guidelines in this document are somewhat specific to deployment of
   collections in the Image Services access system at the University
   of Michigan Digital Library Production Service and should not be
   considered as a generally applicable interpretation of the Dublin
   Core.</I></P>

<P>Image Services uses a somewhat simplified implementation of Dublin
Core. While the <A HREF="http://purl.oclc.org/dc/">Dublin Core
documentation</A> is informative, the following table may be most
useful when preparing data for Image Services.</P>

<P>Keep in mind that databases often have a mix of fields, some that
describe the subject matter, and some that describe the physical
item. In the case of a photograph of architecture, is the photograph
the item or is the architecture the item?&#0160;The answer to this
varies depending on the database (and the curatorial decisions that
went into creating the database). At any rate, it is issues like
this that make the mapping process interesting and challenging.</P>

<P>Again, the goal is to map database/collection specific fields to
the more general Dublin Core fields in order to make searching across
all Image Services databases possible. The collection specific fields
will also be searchable directly in a collection specific search. You
may find that it helps to <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/">try
some of the other collections</A> that are online to see how they are
mapped. Mappings are viewable by looking at a <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?type=detail;cc=bhl;entryid=X-bl000308;viewid=1;sstrt=5;hits=27;q1=huron;cat1=All%20Categories;cross=1;thsz=12;txsz=50;slsz=1;med=1;c=bhl">detailed
record in the cross collection search</A>. It is also useful to look
at <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?type=detail;cc=bhl;entryid=X-bl000308;viewid=1;sstrt=1;hits=1;q1=5635;cat1=All%20Categories;thsz=12;txsz=50;slsz=1;med=1;c=bhl">detailed
records in the collection specific search</A> to pick up nuances of
each collection.</P>

<TABLE BORDER="1">
<TBODY>
   <TR>
      <TD>
         <P><B>Core Category/Field Name</B></P>
      </TD>
      <TD>
         <P><B>Types of Collection Specific Fields Commonly
         Mapped</B></P>
      </TD>
   </TR>
   <TR>
      <TD>
         <P>Creator</P>
      </TD>
      <TD>
         <UL>
            <LI>Name of artist, architect, photographer, creator,
            etc.</LI>
            
            <LI>Tombstone information for artist, architect,
            photographer, creator, etc.</LI>
            
            <LI>Nationality of artist, architect, photographer,
            creator, etc.</LI>
         </UL>
      </TD>
   </TR>
   <TR>
      <TD>
         <P>Title</P>
      </TD>
      <TD>
         <UL>
            <LI>Titles, subtitles, project names.</LI>
            
            <LI>When there is not a formal title, captions, location
            for architecture, and similar fields are sometimes
            mapped to Title.</LI>
         </UL>
      </TD>
   </TR>
   <TR>
      <TD>
         <P>Description</P>
      </TD>
      <TD>
         <UL>
            <LI>Fields that provide <B>physical</B> description of
            the item, such as medium, type, and dimensions.</LI>
            
            <LI>Fields that describe the site or project
            history.</LI>
         </UL>
      </TD>
   </TR>
   <TR>
      <TD>
         <P>Subject</P>
      </TD>
      <TD>
         <UL>
            <LI>Keywords.</LI>
            
            <LI>Subject Terms.</LI>
            
            <LI>Other fields that describe the subject matter. What
            it is of, and what it is about.</LI>
         </UL>
      </TD>
   </TR>
   <TR>
      <TD>
         <P>Date</P>
      </TD>
      <TD>
         <UL>
            <LI>Creation date (or date range)&#0160;that the item was
            created.</LI>
            
            <LI>Date period (e.g., renaissance).</LI>
         </UL>
      </TD>
   </TR>
   <TR>
      <TD>
         <P>Rights</P>
      </TD>
      <TD>
         <UL>
            <LI>Copyright</LI>
            
            <LI>Contact Info (for acquiring permission to use)</LI>
         </UL>
      </TD>
   </TR>
   <TR>
      <TD>
         <P>Source</P>
      </TD>
      <TD>
         <UL>
            <LI>Source. For example, if the image was copied from a
            book, it would be the bibliographic citation. If the
            image was acquired from a vendor, it would be the name of
            the vendor.</LI>
         </UL>
      </TD>
   </TR>
   <TR>
      <TD>
         <P>Publisher</P>
      </TD>
      <TD>
         <UL>
            <LI>The entity responsible for making the item available
            online. In Image Services, this is most commonly your
            organization (e.g., Bentley Historical Library, UM Museum
            of Art, etc.).</LI>
         </UL>
      </TD>
   </TR>
   <TR>
      <TD>
         <P><B>Other Categories/Field Names</B></P>
      </TD>
      <TD>
         <P></P>
      </TD>
   </TR>
   <TR>
      <TD>
         <P>Miscellaneous (not a Core field)</P>
      </TD>
      <TD>
         <UL>
            <LI>Any field that simply does not map well to the above
            options should probably be mapped to Miscellaneous. This
            allows the miscellaneous fields to also be displayed in
            cross collection searches.</LI>
            
            <LI>There may be fields that simply should not be mapped
            to any core fields. It should be questioned whether or
            not these fields should be going online at all. If they
            should, then it is OK to not map them.</LI>
         </UL>
      </TD>
   </TR>
   <TR>
      <TD>
         <P>Main Entry</P>
      </TD>
      <TD>
         <UL>
            <LI>Title and Creator and Date.</LI>
            
            <LI>It is <B>mandatory</B> that one or more fields be
            mapped to Main Entry and that at least one of the fields
            always contains data values. The Main Entry fields are
            used for displaying search results to the user in a cross
            collection search.</LI>
         </UL>
      </TD>
   </TR>
</TBODY>
</TABLE>



</DIV1>
</BODY>
</DLPSDOC>
