<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!-- SPO Editorial Services                  -->
<!-- automatically-generated XML header file -->

<?xml-stylesheet href="../../../pre11-dlxsdocs.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE DLPSDOC PUBLIC "-//UM-DLPS//DTD DLPS Publications//EN" "http://docs.umdl.umich.edu/dlps/docs/dlpsdocs.dtd">
<DLPSDOC>
<TITLE>Preparing Data for Image Services</TITLE>
<HEADER>
<JOURNAL>DLXS Documentation</JOURNAL>
<PUBDATE>2002-07-03 17:14:20 EDT</PUBDATE>
<AUTH1>Weise, John</AUTH1>
<AUTH2></AUTH2>
<DOCTITLE>Preparing Data for Image Services</DOCTITLE>
<VOL>class</VOL>
<ISS>image</ISS>
<FILE>dlxsdocs-image-guidelines-data</FILE>
</HEADER>




<BODY>
<BHEAD>Preparing Data for Image Services</BHEAD>
<DIV1 ID="main">

<P>
<A HREF="mailto:dlxs-help@umich.edu">dlxs-help@umich.edu</A>
</P>

<B>Image Services has always
   tried to make it as easy as possible for you to make your data
   accessible online. The last thing we want to do is impose a set of
   rules that complicate the process. Yet, there may be some fairly
   easy things you can do that would help us out. You may find that
   some also improve the end product because they have received your
   specialized input. The fact is, you probably already do most of
   the things listed below, and  perhaps this will just be a useful
   check list each time you prepare to give us a data update. </B>

<P>Please feel free to ask for clarification on any of these items by
sending email to <A HREF="mailto:jweise@umich.edu">jweise@umich.edu</A>.
Thanks!</P>
<DIV2 ID="descriptivedata">
<H2>Part 1: Descriptive Data</H2>

<OL>
   
  <LI>First of all, please review the <A HREF="image-datareqs.xml">Image Class 
    Data Requirements</A>&#0160;document to understand the minimum requirements 
    for data.</LI>
   
   <LI>Data should be in one of the following formats, listed in
   order of preference:
   
   <OL>
      <LI>Delimited ASCII&#0160;Text File (TAB or comma)</LI>
      
      <LI>FileMaker Pro (3.0 or newer)</LI>
      
      <LI>Microsoft Excel</LI>
      
      <LI>Microsoft Access</LI>
   </OL>
   </LI>
   
   <LI>Data should be in a "flattened" structure rather than a
   relational structure. In other words, all data should be contained
   within a single file, without dependencies on other data files. If
   you are not sure what it means to flatten data, there is a good
   chance your data is already flat. Just ask us, we can tell you!
   
   <UL>
      <LI>It is typically easy to flatten a relational database by
      exporting all of the fields to a new file.</LI>
   </UL>
   </LI>
   
   <LI>We prefer to only receive the data fields that are to go
   online. Alternatively, an accurate list of the fields that are to
   go online could be provided.</LI>
   
   <LI>If the data is submitted in a format that does not include
   field names (e.g., ASCII Text File), then field names should be
   provided in a separate document (even a written list on paper will
   do) and in the exact same order they occur in the data file.</LI>
   
   <LI>If you would like any field names to appear differently online
   than they appear in the data file, please provide the appropriate
   names, paired with the original names. <B>For example</B>, let's
   say you have a field name in FileMaker Pro called "box_no.", but
   you would like it to be called "Box Number" online.</LI>
   
   <LI>If fields are to be combined or split or otherwise modified by
   calculation for online use, all calculations should be taken care
   of prior to sending the data to Image Services.</LI>
   
   <LI>It is highly recommended that you include a "Rights"&#0160;field
   that provides the user with basic copyright information for the
   image. Often this field can contain the same information for all
   records. <B>For example</B>, see the <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry;subview=detail;cc=musart;entryid=X-1862.1;viewid=1">Museum
   of Art's <I>Rights</I> field</A>.</LI>
   
   <LI>There must be a unique record identifier field, and every
   record must have a unique identifier value (e.g., accession
   number, serial number). Please clearly identify the field to be
   used as the unique identifier since sometimes there is more than
   one field that appears to be a unique identifier.
   
   <UL>
      <LI>Records without a unique identifier will not be put
      online.</LI>
      
      <LI>If more than one record has the same identifier value, the
      first occurring record will be put online and the others will
      not.</LI>
   </UL>
   </LI>
   
   <LI>If the data has associated image files, there should be an
   image filename field.
   
   <UL>
      <LI>Even though the unique identifier and image filename are
      often the same, image filenames often need minor adjustments to
      work in the online access system, so it is best for unique
      identifiers and image filenames to be kept in separate fields.
      It is also easier to troubleshoot filenaming problems if the
      filename field only contains filenames for <B>existing</B>
      image files, rather than for every unique identifier whether or
      not a digital image file actually exists. Understandably, this
      is not always feasible.</LI>
      
      <LI>If there are multiple images per record, the image filenames can be in a single repeating field, or in multiple fields. There can even be multiple repeating fields. If there are special relationships among the images of a record, it is worth having a discussion with Image Services to find the best way to enter image filename data.</LI>
      
      <LI>Image filenames may be entered in the database with or without filename extensions. It really does not matter (though it did in the past). Image Services prefers, however, that full filename paths not be included in the image filename field.</LI>
   </UL>
   </LI>
   
   <LI>If the data has associated image files, identify the field
   that most appropriately acts as a "caption" for the image(s). If
   there is not a descriptive field that works well as a caption, the
   image filename field or the unique identifier field may be used
   (something must be used).
   
   <UL>
      <LI>The "caption" field may be a repeating field in cases where
      there are multiple images per record. The repetitions of the
      "caption" field should be synchronized with the repetitions of
      the image filename.</LI>
   </UL>
   </LI>
   
   <LI>You may specify the fields that should be selectable by the
   user for searching. <B>For example</B>, see the <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/u/ummu/simple.html">Media
   Union Library's simple search form</A>. The searchable category
   list is by choice only a subset of the fields that are available
   and viewable in the <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?type=detail;cc=ummu;entryid=X-99-0176;viewid=1;sstrt=11;hits=732;q1=house%20;cat1=All%20Categories;thsz=12;txsz=50;slsz=1;med=1;c=ummu">full
   record</A>.</LI>
   
   <LI>You may specify the fields that should be displayed in the
   search results list. You may also specify the order in which the
   fields should be displayed. <B>For example</B>, the Bentley
   Historical Library has chosen to display the Bentley Item Number
   and the Image Title fields in the <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?type=simple;sstrt=1;q1=Bentley;cat1=All%20Categories;thsz=12;txsz=50;slsz=1;med=1;c=bhl;res=thumbnail">results
   list</A>. Make sure that at least one of these fields has a value
   in every single record. You may also specify different fields for
   each of the results display modes (text only, text with
   thumbnails, slideshow).</LI>
   
   <LI>You may specify the fields, and their order, for the full
   record (a.k.a., "details") display. <B>For example</B>, the
   Bentley Historical Library has chosen to display all of their
   fields in the <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?type=detail;cc=bhl;entryid=X-bl001001;viewid=1;sstrt=1;hits=1012;q1=Bentley;cat1=All%20Categories;thsz=12;txsz=50;slsz=1;med=1;c=bhl">full
   record display</A>.</LI>
   
   <LI>Image Services maps all database specific fields to a set of
   general fields in order to enable searching across collections.
   The general fields are <B>based</B> on Dublin Core. You are
   encouraged to specify the mappings for your database. Optionally,
   you can let us do it the first time, and then you can suggest
   modifications for the next time around. <B>For example</B>, the
   Bentley Historical Library has worked closely with Image Services
   to appropriately map their fields to the <A HREF="http://purl.oclc.org/dc/">Dublin
   Core</A>, as witnessed in the <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?type=detail;cc=bhl;entryid=X-bl001001;viewid=1;sstrt=1;hits=270;q1=michigan%20football;cat1=All%20Categories;cross=1;thsz=12;txsz=50;slsz=1;med=1;c=bhl">full
   record display of a cross-collection search</A>. Once you are
   happy with the mappings, it is generally not necessary to redo the
   mappings with each data update unless fields have been added or
   changes are needed.
   
   <UL>
      <LI>Please see <A HREF="image-dc-guidelines.xml">Guidelines for Mapping 
        to Core Categories for Image Services</A>.</LI>
   </UL>
   </LI>
   
   <LI>Please specify the appropriate full title for the database as
   well as an abbreviation that we can use for efficiency in our
   system. The abbreviation will also be part of the URL. <B>For
   example...</B>
   
      <TABLE BORDER="1">
      <TBODY>
         <TR>
            <TD>
               <P><B>Full Title</B></P>
            </TD>
            <TD>
               <P><B>Abbreviation</B></P>
            </TD>
            <TD>
               <P><B>URL</B></P>
            </TD>
         </TR>
         <TR>
            <TD>
               <P>Bentley Historical Library</P>
            </TD>
            <TD>
               <P>bhl</P>
            </TD>
            <TD>
               <P><A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/b/bhl/">http://images.umdl.umich.edu/b/bhl/</A></P>
            </TD>
         </TR>
         <TR>
            <TD>
               <P>Media Union Library</P>
            </TD>
            <TD>
               <P>ummu</P>
            </TD>
            <TD>
               <P><A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/u/ummu/">http://images.umdl.umich.edu/u/ummu/</A></P>
            </TD>
         </TR>
      </TBODY>
      </TABLE>
   </LI>
   
   <LI>It is often necessary for Image Services to have full administrative access to a
   data file in order to prepare it for online use. Therefore, it is
   preferable that the data file not require a password at any
   level. If a password is required, please remember to provide
   it.</LI>
   
   <LI>If your database uses special characters, it may be necessary
   to translate them to ISO/IEC
   8859-1:1998 Latin Alphabet No. 1 compliant characters. This
   depends, at least, on the operating system and font that was used
   to enter the data. The ISO&#0160;Latin 1 8-bit characters set
   includes only a basic set of special characters. We'll be able to
   tell you if your data has noncompliant characters in it, but often
   it is impossible for us to know what the characters should look
   like. Therefore we may come back to you for help. Proactively, you
   can keep track of each special character that you use and an
   example of the character within the context of a word from your
   database. Sometimes it is necessary to "dumb down" characters. For
   instance, curly quotes are often "dumbed down" to straight quotes
   when we put a database online.</LI>
   
   
  <LI>Finally, if you would like to gain a better overall understanding of how 
    the Image Services access system (a.k.a., Image Class) works, please read 
    <A HREF="image-imageclass.xml">The Image Class</A>.</LI>
</OL>

</DIV2>
<DIV2 ID="imagefiles">
<H2>Part 2: Image Files</H2>

<P>Please remember, these are guidelines, not requirements!</P>

<OL>
   <LI>Master image files should be supplied in the Tagged Image File
   Format (TIF), with or without LZW&#0160;compression. JPEG or other
   types of lossy compression should not be used on the master
   image.</LI>
   
   <LI>Images should be provided on ISO 9660 Level 1 compliant
   CD-ROMs, <B><I>if possible</I></B> We can also accept image files in many other ways, so if the guidelines here do not suit you, we can talk about it.
   
   <UL>
      <LI>In Level 1 (the lowest common denominator, developed with
      DOS file naming limitations in mind):
      
      <UL>
         <LI>A filename may not contain more than eight
         <I>d-characters</I>.<BR/>
         <B>d-characters are capital A to Z,
         digits 0 to 9, and the underscore symbol ( _
         ).</B></LI>
         
         <LI>A Filename Extension may not contain more than three
         <I>d-characters</I>.</LI>
         
         <LI>A directory name may not contain more than eight
         <I>d-characters</I>.</LI>
         
         <LI>A cd name (volume name) may not contain more than 32
         <I>d-characters</I>.</LI>
      </UL>
      </LI>
      
      <LI>Roxio provides a wonderful <A HREF="http://www.roxio.com/en/support/">CD-ROM&#0160;technical
      resource</A> online if you would like more information about CD technology. </LI>
   </UL>
   </LI>
   
   <LI>In general, and especially given the restrictions above, it
   does not work well to try to use highly descriptive filenames.
   Filenames based on unique record IDs, accession numbers, or simple
   serial numbers are often the best. It can be useful to prefix a
   filename with a character or two that categorizes the image files
   in some way. For example, the Bentley Historical Library uses the
   form "BL000001.TIF", where the "BL" simply stands for Bentley
   Library. Accurate record keeping immediately becomes important
   just to keep track of the images in a more descriptive
   fashion.</LI>
   
   <LI>Digital images should be calibrated to a display gamma of 2.2.
   In other words, the image should look best on a computer monitor
   that has been calibrated to a gamma of 2.2.</LI>
   
   <LI>Grayscale image files should have a bit-depth of 8.</LI>
   
   <LI>Color image files should have a bit depth of no more than
   24, which is no more than three 8-bit channels (Red, Green, Blue).
   There must not be alpha or other types of channels.
   
   <UL>
      <LI>It is good that many scanners initially capture more than
      24 bits of color because it improves the overall quality of the
      final image. <B>At this time it is a bad idea to save more than
      24 bits of color</B> to the master image file because very few
      imaging applications know how to use the extra data, and the
      usefulness of the data beyond the initial capture is
      questionable.</LI>
   </UL>
   </LI>
   
   <LI>Image Services prefers not to put bitonal images online, though the
   Digital Library Production Service does for text pages.</LI>
   
   <LI>Very high quality, high resolution master image files are
   desirable. Image Services has advanced methods for putting
   extremely high resolution images online in a way that enables easy
   viewing on the web, so file size is not a concern. The goal is to
   get the best quality image without a) unnecessarily exceeding the
   detail of the original object, and b) exceeding the optical resolution
   of the scanning device. Many scanners offer interpolation as a
   means for achieving resolution beyond the capabilities of the
   hardware. Interpolation must be avoided. It is extremely difficult
   to prescribe appropriate resolutions for materials. Each situation
   is unique. However, the following table offers some guidelines.
   
<UL>

<LI><TABLE BORDER="1">
<TBODY>
         <TR>
            <TD>
               <P><B>Original</B></P>
            </TD>
            <TD>
               <P><B>Resolution (Dots Per Inch)</B></P>
            </TD>
         </TR>
         <TR>
            <TD>
               <P>Photographic Print</P>
            </TD>
            <TD>
               <P>400 - 600 DPI</P>
            </TD>
         </TR>
         <TR>
            <TD>
               <P>35mm Film</P>
            </TD>
            <TD>
               <P>2700 DPI</P>
            </TD>
         </TR>
         <TR>
            <TD>
               <P>4x5 Film</P>
            </TD>
            <TD>
               <P>900 - 1800 DPI</P>
            </TD>
         </TR>
         <TR>
            <TD>
               <P>Papyri</P>
            </TD>
            <TD>
               <P>600 DPI</P>
            </TD>
         </TR>
         <TR>
            <TD>
               <P>Manuscripts</P>
            </TD>
            <TD>
               <P>400-600 DPI</P>
            </TD>
         </TR>
</TBODY>    
  </TABLE>
      </LI>
   </UL>
   </LI>
   
   <LI>Sharpening of an image is typically an essential and integral
   part of scanning. At the same time, great care should be taken to
   not over sharpen an image. An <I>unsharp mask</I> filter is a
   preferred method of sharpening available in Adobe Photoshop and
   many other imaging applications.</LI>
   
   <LI>If a scan is skewed, it is best to adjust it on the scanner
   and rescan. Digital deskewing (rotation by small degrees) degrades
   the image. Rotation by 90, 180, 270 degrees is fine and does not
   degrade the image.</LI>
</OL>

</DIV2>
<DIV2 ID="resources">
<H2>Resources</H2>

<UL>
   <LI>The University of Michigan, <A HREF="http://www.umdl.umich.edu/">Digital
   Library Production Service</A>, <A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/">Image
   Services</A> is happy to provide free consultation on best
   practices for database creation and digital imaging. Please
   contact <A HREF="mailto:umdl-help@umich.edu">umdl-help@umich.edu</A>.</LI>
   
   <LI><A HREF="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/">Image Services</A>
   provides high quality photographic and digitization services at
   competitive rates. We have a variety of methods, including 4x5
   photography and film digitization, flatbed scanning, 35mm film
   scanning, and direct digital photography. Contact <A HREF="mailto:dlps-digit@umich.edu">dlps-digit@umich.edu</A>
   for more info.</LI>
   
   <LI>Image Services also hosts a wide variety of image databases
   online, primarily serving the University Library and University of
   Michigan, and extending to other institutions as well. Contact
   <A HREF="mailto:umdl-help@umich.edu">umdl-help@umich.edu</A> for more
   information.</LI>
   
   <LI><A HREF="http://www.rlg.org/visguides/">Guides to Quality in
   Visual Resource Imaging</A>, from the Digital Library Federation
   and Research Libraries Group.</LI>
   
   
   <LI><A HREF="http://www.rlg.org/preserv/mtip2000.html">Moving
   Theory Into Practice</A> by Anne R. Kenney and Oya Y. Rieger.</LI>

</UL>
</DIV2>
<P>

modified 10/5/2000, jweise@umich.edu</P>
</DIV1>
</BODY>
</DLPSDOC>
